這里是1959年勒芒24小時耐力賽的現場直播
This is live coverage of the 1959 24 Hours of Le Mans.
比賽已經進行到了一半
We've reached the halfway point
到目前為止  我們目睹了由卡羅爾·謝爾比駕駛的
and so far witnessed Aston Martin number 5,
阿斯頓馬丁5號
driven by Carroll Shelby,
在過去的一小時里增加了大量行駛里程
making great gains in the last hour.
如果他繼續保持當前的速度
If he keeps this pace up,
極速車王
他就有可能贏得...
he could have a chance at the...
燃油
他要進站了
He's coming in.
他要進站了  快點  行動起來
He's coming in. Let's go, let's go.
-拿輪胎  -快點  行動起來
- Tires! - Let's go, let's go.
我知道你們累了  加把勁  速戰速決
I know you're tired, but come on, let's make this fast.
動起來  動起來  快
Move, move, move!
它有點過熱  但沒什么大問題
She's running a little hot, but we're good.
輪胎還有抓地力
Tires are still gripping.
-著火了  -油點著了
- Fire! - The fuel! Fire!
-謝爾比  你著火了  - 把那條毯子拿來
- Shelby, it's you! - Grab that blanket!
放開我  放開
Get off me! Off!
你還好嗎
You okay?
給油箱加油啊
Fill the tank!
-謝爾比  你剛剛...  -我身上著火了嗎
- Shelby, you just... - Am I on fire?
我他媽身上著火了嗎
Am I on goddamn fire?
-你沒著火  -那就趕快給油箱加油
- No, you're not on fire. - Fill the damn tank!
-加油  -加油
- Fill the tank. - Fill the tank.
準備好
Get it ready!
-我現在在什么位置  艾迪  -領先兩圈
- Where am I, Eddie? - Two laps up, my friend.
車準備好了
Car's yours.
上吧
Go get 'em.
由卡羅爾·謝爾比駕駛的阿斯頓馬丁5號
Aston Martin number 5, driven by Carroll Shelby,
在比賽將要結束時
has maintained his lead
保持了領先地位
as we're nearing the final minutes of the race.
謝爾比
Shelby.
方格旗已經出現了
The checkered flag is out.
觀眾們翹首以盼
The crowd are on their feet.
謝爾比
Shelby.
贏得了冠軍
takes the title!
一個美國人贏了勒芒耐力賽
An American wins Le Mans.
謝爾比
Shelby.
卡羅爾·謝爾比
Carroll Shelby.
什么
What?
這事你不能再無視下去了
This is something you can't ignore anymore.
我吃藥啊  藥片有用的
Oh, I take the pills. The pills work.
過快的心率  比如每分鐘130下
An elevated heart rate, say 130 BPM,
即使持續時間很短
sustained even for a short period,
你也很有可能會心跳驟停
you run a critical risk of cardiac arrest.
-那我就開一些短程比賽  -那樣也沒用
- I'll race shorter format then. - That's not gonna work.
我可以開納斯卡車賽  F1錦標賽
Well, I could race NASCAR. Formula One.
你的心臟瓣膜撐不住了  謝爾比
The valve is shot, Shelby.
這件事很嚴重
This is as serious as it gets.
在我看來  你今天能坐在這里就已經是萬幸了
In my opinion, you're lucky to be sitting here today.
我確實覺得自己很幸運
Well, I feel real lucky.
我覺得我是全世界最幸運的人
Luckiest guy on earth.
在七千轉時
There's a point.
有一個臨界點  一切都變得虛無
7,000 RPM where everything fades.
車失去了重量
The machine becomes weightless.
直接消失了
Just disappears.
當心點  伙計
Watch it, buddy!
只留下一具軀殼
And all that's left is a body
在時空中穿梭
moving through space and time.
七千轉
7,000 RPM.
就是那個臨界點
That's where you meet it.
它會向你提出一個問題
It asks you a question.
一個終極的問題
The only question that matters.
"你究竟是誰"
"Who are you?"
現在駕駛法拉利的是馮·特里普斯
Now, it's von Trips in the Ferrari,
他來到了下坡急彎
coming into the corkscrew.
我給你打了三次電話  你一次都沒回我
Hey, I called you three times, and you never answer the phone.
他在延遲剎車
He's braking late.
他創造了新的圈速紀錄
Oh! He sets a new lap record!
每個電話我都會接
I answer the phone every time it rings.
不  先生  你沒接
No, sir, you do not.
我接了
Yes, I do.
不  你沒接
No, you don't.
一個月前  這輛車還好好的
A month ago, this car was fine.
現在都沒法發動了
Now, it won't even start.
每次一發動  就砰砰作響
And when it does, it's, "Boom, boom, boom!"
我把這車開出車道
When I pull out of the driveway,
路旁的狗都要嚇出心臟病
the dog has a heart attack.
我只希望你能把這車修好
All I'm asking is for you to make it like it was.
你把進氣閥和火花塞憋住了
Yeah, you've coked up the inlet valves and the plugs.
車沒問題
Nothing wrong with the car,
有問題的是開車方式
just the way it's being driven.
開車方式
The way it's being driven?
燃料太多  火星不夠
Too much fuel, not enough spark.
所以它才會打不著火
That's what's making her misfire.
你想用人話跟我解釋一遍嗎
You wanna run that by me in English?
好吧  先生
All right, sir.
你看啊
So...
那邊那輛車  是輛跑車
that there, that is a sport car.
你必須用開跑車的方法來開她
You have to drive her like a sport car.
如果你像個學校老師一樣來開她
If you drive her like a school teacher,
它就會堵塞  知道嗎
she'll clog up. All right?
等五千轉的時候再換擋  別兩千轉就換
Try changing up at 5,000 RPM, not two.
開車的時候認真點  干脆利落
Drive like you mean it. Hard and tight.
它就會順暢無阻了
She'll run clean.
你是在跟我說我不知道怎么開自己的車嗎
Are you telling me I don't know how to drive my own car?
不是
No.
但如果你問我的話  你確實駕馭不了這車
But if you ask me, this isn't your car.
普利茅斯或者斯圖貝克這種車更適合你
Your car's more a Plymouth or a Studebaker.
你是對我有什么意見嗎  伙計
You and me have a problem, buddy?
我沒有意見  我曾經有輛名爵
I don't have a problem. I had an MG.
我的車開著就挺好
Mine ran just fine.
去你的  你這個狗屁英國佬
Screw you, you limey prick.
我要退款
I want my money back.
文明一點  退給你就是了
Oh, behave. I'd give it to ya.
但你上個月的保養費還沒給呢
But you haven't paid for last month's service yet.
在這個國家  顧客就是上帝
This country, the customer's always right.
你沒聽說過嗎
You ever hear that?
聽過  聽過
Yeah. Yeah.
完全就是屁話
Utter nonsense.
記好了  我把定時鏈調快了
Now remember, I advanced the timing,
所以剛開始車會有點抖
so a smidge twitchy in first.
把轉速提上去  就這樣  轉速提上去
Get the revs up. Good lad. Revs up.
再見
Ta-ra.
又是一個滿意而歸的顧客嗎
Another satisfied customer?
何事需要效勞  小姐
Can I help you, miss?
剛剛那輛不是名爵的MGA 1500嗎
Wasn't that an MGA 1500?
你很懂車嘛
You know your cars.
我很喜歡車
Well, I like them.
我喜歡發動機的轟鳴聲
I love the sound they make.
那聲音直接穿過你的身體
The way it goes right through you.
沒錯
Right.
那種振動
That vibration.
我的車是那輛鑲木板的
Mine's the wood-paneled
福特鄉紳
Country Squire...
就停在街對面
across the street.
一輛改裝的大馬力車
A real hot rod.
是嗎
Oh, yeah?
-開得快嗎  -非常快
- Is it fast? - Very.
等等  你是哪種女孩
Wait a second. What type of girl are ya?
我這種女孩喜歡聞汽油味
Type of girl who likes the smell of wet gasoline.
和燒過的橡膠味
Burnt rubber.
那你有點離經叛道  不是嗎
Oh, what, are you some kind of a deviant, are ya?
還不是因為我嫁給了你
Well, only since I married you.
加爾  怎么回事
Hey, Gar, what's going on?
出事了
Something's up.
你好  李
Hi, Lee.
聽著  銀行這事他沒你確定
Listen, he isn't as sure as you are about the banks.
我也不確定這事...
I'm not as sure about this...
進展如何
How's this going out?
-唐  怎么回事  -我不知道
- Don, what's going on? - I don't know.
福特先生  歡迎來到車間
Mr. Ford, welcome to the room.
下午好  福特先生
Good afternoon, Mr. Ford.
幸會  先生
Nice to see you, sir.
停工  畢比先生
Shut it down, Mr. Beebe.
約翰
John!
全部停下
All stop.
聽見那聲音了嗎
Hear that?
那就是福特汽車公司
That's the sound of the Ford Motor Company...
要倒閉的聲音
out of business.
1899年  我的祖父亨利·福特
In 1899, my grandfather, Henry, by God, Ford...
從愛迪生照明公司走回家
was walking home from Edison Illumination
他那時剛上完兩輪班
after working a double shift.
他左思右想
He was ruminating.
那個清晨  他產生了一個想法
That morning, he had himself an idea
那個想法改變了世界
that changed the world.
65年過去了
Sixty-five years
在生產了四千七百萬輛車之后
and 47 million automobiles later,
他將留下什么
what shall be his legacy?
雪佛蘭羚羊排出的尾氣
Getting it in the tail pipe from a Chevy Impala.
通用汽車旗下雪佛蘭的暢銷車型
我希望你們做如下事項
Here's what I want you to do.
走回家
Walk home.
你們在走的時候  我希望你們能好好思索
While you're walking, I want you to ruminate.
誰能帶著想法走進我的辦公室
Man comes to my office with an idea,
誰就能保住工作
that man keeps his job.
其他的二流失敗者...
Rest of you second-best losers...
就待在家里吧
stay home.
你不屬于福特公司
You don't belong at Ford.
謝爾比
Shelby!
我看見你了  該起床了  伙計
I see you. Up and at 'em, buddy.
-走開  -快點  你可以的
- Go away. - Come on. You can do it.
快起床吧  寶貝
Come on, baby.
八點半了  該出發了
8:30 a.m., time to roll.
快來
Let's go.
-快來快來  -滾開
- Let's go. Let's go, go, go. - Go away.
已經八點半了  寶貝  該出發了
It's 8:30 a.m., baby. Time to roll.
走吧
Come on.
你好啊  菲爾
Hey, Phil.
你好啊  鮑勃
Hey, Bob.
謝爾比在嗎
Is Shelby here?
很難說
it's touch and go.
謝爾比  你起得可真早
Shelby, you're up bright and early.
早起的鳥兒有蟲吃嘛  老爹
Well, early bird gets the worm, Pops.
好吧  你擔心誰
All right, who you worried about?
瑞德·法里斯和比爾·拉什頓
Well, you got Red Faris and Bill Rushton.
他們都開327發動機的
They're all in 327s.
科爾維特  那邦杜蘭特呢
Corvettes. What about Bondurant?
邦杜蘭特嗎  他還在給...
Bondurant? Well, he's still driving...
-謝爾比先生  能給我簽個名嗎  -沃什伯恩開車
- Mr. Shelby, can I get an autograph? - for Washburn.
614號
Number 614.
-太感謝了  -好了  放輕松
- Thank you so much. - All right, just relax. All right.
科爾維特那些車都不足掛齒
We're gonna eat those Vettes for breakfast.
我們更輕  更快
We're lighter, we're faster,
如果這些都沒用的話  我們更野
and that don't work, we're nastier.
各位爸爸們  在比賽開始之前
Hey, Dad, before the race starts,
帶著你們的兒子來柳泉賽道看看吧...
take your son over to the Willow Springs...
菲爾  今天對我們手下留點情  老兄
Hey, Phil. Hey, take it easy on us today, bud.
有什么問題嗎
You all right?
美國賽車俱樂部標準第2b節第15.4條
Paragraph 15.4, section 2b of the SCCA standard
規定了所有AF級賽車的后備箱容量
dictates all AF class cars must have
尺寸至少要長20英寸  寬12英寸  高6英寸
minimum trunk space of 20 inches by 12 inches by 6 inches.
你這車連后備箱都合不上
Your trunk doesn't close.
-因此這輛車不符合標準  -等等  什么
- Ergo car fails standard. - Wait, wait, wait. What?
因此這輛車沒有資格
Ergo car is disqualified from
-參加A級比賽  -不不不  聽著
- said Class A competition. - No, no, no. Look, look, look.
讓我問你個問題好嗎
Can I ask you a question, all right?
當你還是個小男孩的時候  你有沒有想過
When you were a little boy, did you think,
"等我長大了
"When I grow up,
我想去傳說中的柳泉賽道
I want to go to the fabled Willow Springs Raceway,
然后我想執行
and I want to enforce
美國賽車俱樂部標準第2b節第15.4條中
paragraph 15.4, section 2b
關于后備箱容量的規定"
of the SCCA regulations on luggage capacity"?
-好了  就這樣  -你想過嗎
- All right, that's it. - Did you?
我要取消你和你的隊伍的參賽資格
I'm ruling you and your team disqualified from this race.
這該不會是蘭斯·瑞文特羅吧
Well, if it isn't Lance Reventlow.
-謝爾比  -你最近怎么樣  蘭斯
- Shelby. - How you doing, Lance?
-老爹  -你好啊  蘭斯
- Pops. - Hey, Lance.
請允許我向你們介紹迪特·沃斯
Allow me to introduce Dieter Voss.
他在杰克遜維爾運營著布魯莫斯保時捷車隊
Runs Brumos Porsche out of Jacksonville.
久仰沃斯先生大名
Oh, I know all about Mr. Voss.
你可是用那輛阿巴斯在賽季取得了輝煌戰績啊  先生
You're having a hell of a season with that Abarth, sir.
-你那輛福特眼鏡蛇也是戰果累累  -多謝夸獎
- Seeing results for your Cobra, too. - Thank you.
你手下那個叫邁爾斯的挺不錯
Your guy Miles is impressive.
-你還在關注邁爾斯  -沒錯
- Oh, you following Miles? - Oh, yes.
他在1961年贏得了美國汽車俱樂部競速賽冠軍
Well, he was a USAC road racing champ in '61.
他贏下了派克峰登山賽
He won the Pikes Peak Hill Climb.
他連續三年贏得美國賽車俱樂部C級冠軍賽
He was SCCA C-class champion three years in a row
開的還是那輛他自己造的破名爵
in this piece-of-shit MG he built himself.
我們聽說他很難搞
We heard he's, difficult.
什么  肯嗎  不不  肯就是一只小狗狗
What, Ken? No, no. Ken's a puppy dog.
蘭斯  告訴他事實  你跟肯比賽過
Hey, Lance, tell the man. You've raced against Ken.
談不上比賽吧  幾乎都是我落后
Oh, I've driven more behind him than against him.
布魯莫斯正在找車手
Well, Brumos is looking for a driver
來駕駛我們在賽百靈耐力賽中的2號車
for our number two car at Sebring.
-是嗎  -這怎么可能
- Is that right? - How is that even possible?
你覺得你手下的邁爾斯可以嗎
Think your guy Miles can make the grade?
-肯這個人...  -他有沒有這么做  伙計
- Oh, well, Ken... - Is he, mate? Hey!
吉姆  他有沒有把他所有的行李
Jim! Is he putting his bloody carryal
-都放進你的后備箱  -什么
- in your trunk? - What?
這是可自由裁量的違規
Discretionary infraction.
各位  失陪一會
Gentlemen, excuse me a moment.
說實話  肯就是為了賽百靈耐力賽而生的
To be honest, Ken was born for Sebring.
這里面沒有哪句話規定了后備箱尺寸
Nothing in there about my trunk
也沒規定你那可愛的小行李箱的尺寸
and your lovely little portmanteau.
你拿的是1962年那版的老標準
You're holding the '62 edition of the SCCA.
你可以把這張該死的貼紙
And you can stick this bloody sticker
貼在見不得光的地方
where the sun don't shine.
比爾  有什么問題嗎  比爾
Hey, Bill. What seems to be the problem, Bill?
問題就是這位比爾是個混蛋
The problem is that Bill here is an arsehole.
-他不是真心的  -他就是真心的
- No, he doesn't mean that. - Oh, yes, he does. Yes, he does.
不  他真的覺得比爾就是個混蛋
No, he really does think that Bill is an arsehole.
-我只是在盡我的職責  -別急  比爾
- I'm just doing my job here. - Hang on. Bill, Bill, Bill.
依我的經驗看  肯定有...聽我說
In my experience, there is... Listen to me.
一般這種事  肯定有折中辦法
Something like this, there's always a middle ground.
-好嗎  肯是有點過分  -我只是在盡我的職責
- All right? Now, Ken's outta line. - And I'm just doing my job.
這我也理解
I understand you are.
你也知道他在比賽日的表現
You know how he gets on a race day.
你清楚的  不是嗎
You know that. All right?
你也沒必要因為一個后備箱就取消我們的比賽資格
But you're not gonna DQ us over a trunk.
-什么  -你看見那家伙了嗎
- What? - You see that guy?
興致勃勃的
Got his tail up.
高興了嗎  比爾
Happy, Bill?
比爾  我來處理吧  我來跟他談談
Bill, I'll handle it. I'll talk to him.
我來跟他談談  你就好好去享受今天吧
I'll talk to him. You just go and have a great day.
各位  餓了嗎
Hey, folks, feeling hungry?
那不妨去零食吧轉轉...
Head on over to the snack bar...
該死
Shit.
斗牛犬
Bulldog.
你知道剛剛我在跟誰談話嗎
You know who that was I was just talking to?
比爾
Bill.
-在那之前  -不知道
- Before that. - No.
是迪特·沃斯
It was Dieter Voss.
他是哪位
Who's that?
他運營著保時捷車隊  肯
He runs Porsche, Ken.
是個德國的小汽車公司  你或許有所耳聞
It's a little German car company. Maybe you heard of it.
好吧
All right.
他想讓你代表他們參加賽百靈耐力賽
He wanted you to drive at Sebring.
但他聽說你很難搞
But he'd heard you were difficult.
我還以為我們對德國人看法相同
I thought we felt the same way about, Germans.
你喜歡輸嗎  肯
Do you like losing, Ken?
你說什么
Excuse me?
你聽見了
Oh, you heard me.
我不會輸
I don't lose.
沒有贊助商  你就沒有車  肯
Without sponsors, you get no car, Ken.
據我所知  所有的職業賽車手
And last I checked, the professionals
-都有輛車  -謝爾
- all have a car. - Shel!
沒車你根本贏不了美國賽車俱樂部的比賽
You cannot win the SCCA without one.
如果你贏不了 那就是輸了
If you're not winning, you are losing.
別逼我用這玩意給你的腦門來一下
Don't make me lamp this at your head.
你大老遠地把你兒子帶來這里
Did you bring your son all the way out here
是為了讓他來看你被取消比賽資格
to watch you get disqualified
還是為了讓他見識你這副混蛋模樣
or just act like a jackass?
牛逼
Damn!
你身體力行地回答了這個問題
Well, that answers that.
彼得
Peter...
有什么事嗎  先生們
May I help you, gentlemen?
肯·邁爾斯有限公司
外國車專家
大修
發動機調校
肯·邁爾斯在嗎
Yes, is Ken Miles here?
不在
No.
我們想跟邁爾斯先生談談
We need to speak to Mr. Miles.
我是他妻子
I'm his wife.
歡迎來到1963年柳泉賽道競速賽
Welcome to the 1963 Willow Springs 100.
十二輛車將在四十圈的比賽中進行角逐
Twelve cars will be competing in this 40-lap race.
肯  你的擋風玻璃怎么了
Hey, Ken, what happened to your shield?
這是新設計
New design.
看來比賽即將開始
Well, it looks like we're about to begin.
賽車已經完成了暖胎圈
The cars have completed their warm-up lap.
綠旗已出
The green flag is out...
賽車正在接近起點線
and they're approaching the starting line.
來吧
Here we go.
該死的
Oh, bloody hell.
肯·邁爾斯目前處于落后位置
Ken Miles has fallen behind.
學學怎么開車吧  蠢貨
Learn to drive, you pillock!
謝爾比  你懷念這些嗎
So, Shelby, do you miss it?
你好啊  薩姆
Hey, Sam.
勒芒24小時耐力賽冠軍得主  忽然之間就退役了
Guy wins the 24-hour Le Mans, suddenly retires,
開始賣車了
starts selling cars.
這說不通
It just don't make sense.
當然  除非謠言是真的
Well, unless the rumors are true, of course.
什么謠言  薩姆
Oh, what rumors would those be, Sam?
卡羅爾·謝爾比不開車了  因為他沒那個膽量了
That Carroll Shelby quit driving 'cause he lost his nerve.
下個彎我要延遲制動超你車  鮑勃
I'm gonna out-brake you on the next turn, Bob.
想得美  鮑勃
Nice try, Bob.
肯·邁爾斯完成了一次漂亮的超車
Nice move from Ken Miles.
還剩22圈
Twenty-two laps remaining,
目前領先的是菲爾·希爾和丹·格尼
with Phil Hill and Dan Gurney in the lead.
今天的柳泉賽道真是精彩紛呈
It's been an incredible day here at Willow Springs,
我們也目睹了一些激動人心的車技
and we've seen some exciting driving.
四十圈的比賽還剩下最后一圈
With just one lap remaining in this 40-lap race,
馬上就要進入最后階段了
we're coming to the final stretch.
丹·格尼在比賽的大部分時間里都處于領先...
Dan Gurney has been leading the pack for most of the...
18號  瑞德·法瑞斯  脫離賽道
Number 18, Red Faris, is off the track.
所以目前丹·格尼領先
That leaves Dan Gurney for the lead
后面緊跟著經驗豐富的肯·邁爾斯
followed by journeyman Ken Miles.
輪到你了  丹
Now for you, Dan.
他們即將經過最后一個彎道
And they're coming around the last turn.
格尼依舊領先
Gurney is still in the lead
肯·邁爾斯緊隨其后
with Ken Miles hot on his heels.
邁爾斯在找缺口超車
Miles is looking for an opening.
等等
Not yet.
快呀
Come on.
格尼能在最后的直道擋住他嗎
Can Gurney hold him off in the final straight?
再等等
Not yet.
格尼在擋他
Gurney is blocking him out.
就現在
Now.
邁爾斯沖上了路肩
Miles goes for the shoulder.
這一下很漂亮  肯
Nice move, Ken.
現在兩輛車并駕齊驅了
They're wheel to wheel.
加把勁啊
Come on.
雪佛蘭科爾維特和福特眼鏡蛇在終點前的對決
It's Corvette versus Cobra for the finish.
肯·邁爾斯完成了不可思議的終場逆襲
An incredible finish for Ken Miles.
讓人意想不到
Didn't see that one coming.
他雖然難搞  但車技不錯
He's difficult but good.
大家請為這場精彩比賽中的每一位選手送上掌聲
Let's give everyone a hand for one heck of a race.
這我可得喝杯好茶
That calls for a nice cup of tea.
我去燒水
I'll put the kettle on.
上來
Hop in.
? 我 ?
♪ I'm ♪
? 快快樂樂 ?
♪ H-a-p-p-y ♪
? 我快快樂樂 ?
♪ I'm h-a-p-p-y ♪
? 我確定一定以及肯定自己快快樂樂 ?
♪ I know I am, I'm sure I am I'm h-a-p-p-y ♪
老爹  給這玩意裱個框
Pops, frame this.
我們贏了
We did it.
出了什么事
What's wrong?
國稅局的人來了
The IRS came.
他們封了修車店
They've padlocked the garage.
好好睡吧  彼得
All right, Petey.
幾年前...
A couple of years ago...
你說過我們有儲蓄
you said we'd a nest egg.
沒錯
Correct.
幾年前你就說過
A couple of years ago.
沒錯
Correct.
所以我得說清楚  我們破產了
So just to be clear, we are buggered.
確實
Absolutely.
什么都沒了嗎
As in totally?
可以說是分文不剩  身無長物
As in, not a bean, or a pot in which to piss.
備件  存貨  都沒了
Spares, stock, all gone.
工具  我的工具還都被鎖在了里面
Tools. My tools are locked up in there.
我會想辦法解決的
I'll figure something out.
福特公司
1945年
In 1945...
我們的士兵們打完仗回了家
our soldiers came home.
他們回家做的第一件事是什么呢
What was the first thing that they did?
做愛
They had sex.
十七年后
Seventeen years later,
當年出生的那些嬰兒都長大了
those babies, they've grown.
他們找了工作
And they've got jobs.
也考了駕照
They've got licenses.
但他們不想跟他們的父母一樣
But they do not wanna drive the same dull 50s cars
開著五十年代的老舊車型
that their parents drove.
如今的孩子  想讓自己有魅力
You see, kids today, they want glamour.
想讓自己有性吸引力
They want sex appeal.
想追求更快的速度
They want to go fast.
先生們
Gentlemen...
福特汽車公司是時候開始
it's time for the Ford Motor Company
參賽了
to go racing.
我們已經在參賽了  艾亞科卡
We're already in racing, Iacocca.
納斯卡車賽嗎
NASCAR?
這只是地區性的  先生
It's... it's regional, sir.
如果你去看電影  或者翻開一本雜志
If you go to the movies, you open up a magazine,
你不會看到來自溫斯頓-塞勒姆的好男孩組合
you don't see good ol' boys from Winston-Salem.
你看見的都是...
You see...
索菲婭·羅蘭
Sophia Loren...
莫尼卡·維蒂
Monica Vitti.
007可不會開福特出任務  先生
James Bond does not drive a Ford, sir.
那是因為他是個敗類
That's because he's a degenerate.
沒錯吧
See?
天吶  我倒想做個敗類
God, I'd like to be a degenerate.
給我一點時間  先生
just give me one second here, sir.
這是你展示的一部分嗎
Is this part of it?
這有什么意義嗎  艾亞科卡
Is this going anywhere, Iacocca?
等等  先生
Just a second, sir.
好了  好了  可以了
All right, all right, that's enough.
先生  麻煩您再等我...
Sir, if you just bear with me...
關掉  開燈
Turn it off. Lights.
李  在過去的三年里
Lee, in the last three years,
在你和你的營銷團隊的帶領下
you and your marketing team...
公司經歷了美國史上最嚴重的銷量暴跌
have presided over the worst sales slump in US history.
福特先生到底為什么要聽你的
Why exactly should Mr. Ford listen to you?
因為一直以來我們都想錯了
Because we've been thinking wrong.
法拉利
Ferrari.
在最近五次勒芒賽中  法拉利贏了四次
Now, they have won four out of the last five Le Mans.
我們得像法拉利一樣思考
We need to think like Ferrari.
法拉利一年造的車
Ferrari makes fewer cars
還沒有我們一天造的多
in a year than we make in a day.
我們在廁紙上花的錢
We spend more on toilet paper
都比他們在生產上的全部投入要高
than they do on their entire output.
你還想讓我們像他們一樣思考
You want us to think like them?
恩佐·法拉利會名留青史
Enzo Ferrari will go down in history
被稱為史上最偉大的汽車制造者
as the greatest car manufacturer of all time.
為什么
Why?
是因為他造的車最多嗎
Is it because he built the most cars?
不
No.
而是因為他的車所蘊含的意義
It's because of what his cars mean.
勝利
Victory.
法拉利在勒芒賽上取勝了
Ferrari wins at Le Mans.
人們...他們想要分享這種勝利
People, they, they want some of that victory.
如果福特的標志意味著勝利呢
What if the Ford badge meant victory?
而且這種意味被重要的人群認可
And meant it where it counts,
也就是那群史上第一批兜里有錢的
with the first group of 17-year-olds in history
十七歲青少年
with money in their pockets?
這要花上好長時間
This would take years.
幾十年去測試和研發
Decades to test and develop...
還得有一個能打敗法拉利的賽車團隊
a race team capable of taking out Ferrari.
法拉利破產了
Ferrari's bankrupt.
恩佐把他賺到的每一分錢都花在追求完美上了
Enzo has spent every lira he's got chasing perfection,
而您猜怎么著
and you know something?
他做到了
He got there.
但如今他破產了
But now he's broke.
扣押
你不必放棄賽車
You don't have to give up racing
去找一份正職  肯
to get a bloody day job, Ken.
我覺得有必要
I think I do.
我已經玩夠了
Now, I've had my fun.
是時候供養家庭
It's time to put food on the table...
成長起來了
and grow up.
修車店無法支撐我們支付賬單
The garage didn't pay the bills.
而且如今還被扣押了
Now it's locked up.
賽車同樣也不能幫我們付賬單
Racing doesn't pay them either,
更別說我還總是贏呢
and I keep winning.
對啊  因為你很厲害
Yeah, because you're good.
但我不太遵守規則
But I can't play the game.
我不是那種善于團隊合作的人
I'm not what they call a people person.
-這可不一定  -而且我已經45歲了
- You don't say. - And I'm 45 years old.
你真覺得我還會有所改變嗎
Do you really think I'm gonna change?
我永遠也不會有什么很好的發展了
I'm never gonna get the good rise.
我開始得太晚了
I started too late.
那是因為你參戰了
Because you fought in the bloody war.
如果你不賽車了  你會變得讓人難以忍受的
If you stop, you'll be bloody insufferable.
我們別再繞圈子了  已經結束了
Let's quit going round the Wrekin. It's over.
想想好的那面
Let's look on the bright side.
如今我可以養老享福
Now I can get fat and old,
養養玫瑰  吃吃豬肉派
trim the roses, and eat pork pies.
法拉利
不好意思
Scusa.
拜托  不能拍照
Please, no photos.
拜托了
Prego.
-放松點  -你得理解
- Relax, will you? - You gotta understand.
這就像是黑手黨出現
This is like the Mafia showing up
要買走自由女神像
to buy the Statue of Liberty.
如今是反過來的
Kind of the opposite, actually.
如果媒體得到風聲  就要出大亂子了
The press gets wind of this, the shit will hit the Fangio.
李·艾亞科卡  福特汽車
Lee Iacocca, Ford Motor.
弗蘭科·格茲  法拉利
Franco Gozzi, Ferrari.
那是記者嗎
Journalists?
不不  艾亞科卡先生  不是的
No, no, Mr. Iacocca, no.
那是我們的攝影師
It's our cameras.
只是為了見證歷史
Just for history.
4L科倫坡發動機
Four-liter Colombo engine.
每個發動機都由一個人獨立組裝完成
One man assembles the entire engine by himself.
變速器由另一個人組裝
Another man assembles the transmission.
一切都是手工制造
Everything hand-built.
太漂亮了
Bellissimo.
賽車部
Racing Department.
李
Lee.
那位就是
That's him.
我們兩個公司合并后會形成兩個實體
This merger between our companies will form two entities.
福特-法拉利
Ford-Ferrari,
福特控股90%
90 percent owned by Ford,
控制所有產品
who controls all production.
第二  法拉利-福特  賽車團隊
Secondly, Ferrari-Ford, the race team,
法拉利控股90%
90 percent owned by Ferrari.
為了辦妥這事  福特將支付...
In order to secure this, Ford will pay the sum...
失陪
Excuse me.
他需要一點時間來讀這份合同
He will need some time to read this.
請便
Please.
好的  當然了
Yeah, of course.
我要找菲亞特的董事長
阿涅利
我有照片要給你看
快點
Pronto.
我在
你有什么要說的嗎
恩佐繼續享有完全控制權
公司一千八百萬賣給我
吃完了  謝謝
All done, thank you.
"先生們
"Gentlemen,
只有一個小問題
only one small question.
有關我的賽車項目"
It concerns my race program."
"如果我想參加勒芒賽
"If I wish to race Le Mans,
而你們不希望我參加勒芒賽
and you do not wish for me to race Le Mans...
那我們是參加還是不參加"
"Do we or do we not go?"
聽著  在這種可能性極小的情況下
Look, in that highly unlikely scenario...
如果我們無法達成一致...
if we just can't agree...
那么  是的
then, yes.
我是說  不行
I mean, no.
你是對的
You are correct.
你不能參加
You do not go.
"我作為一名制造者
"My integrity as a constructor,
一個男人  一個意大利人
"as a man, as an Italian,
被你們的提案深深地侮辱了"
"is deeply insulted by your proposal."
"滾回密歇根去"
"Go back to Michigan."
"滾回你那龐大丑陋的工廠去"
"Back to your big, ugly factory."
"滾回你那龐大丑陋的工廠
"Back to your big, ugly factory,
去制造丑陋的小汽車"
making its ugly, little cars."
"告訴你那頑固的老板
"Tell your pigheaded boss that
他這些自以為是的管理層
"all his, uh, smug executives
都是一文不值的王八蛋"
"are worthless sons of whores."
告訴他  他不是亨利·福特
Tell him he's not Henry Ford.
他是亨利·福特二世
He's Henry Ford II.
我餓了  我們去吃東西吧
底特律獨立報
菲亞特收購法拉利
恩佐保留完全控制權  賽車部門保持獨立
福特遭拒絕
他耍了我們
He played us.
恩佐那個老家伙本來就沒打算賣給我們
Old Man Enzo had no intention of selling to us.
他是利用我們來抬價
He used us to up his price...
讓我們公司蒙羞  還侮辱了你的領導力
embarrass our company and insult your leadership.
整件事從一開始就不是個好主意
It was a bad idea from the start.
他到底說了什么
What exactly did he say?
他說福特制造丑陋的小汽車
He said Ford makes ugly little cars,
還說我們的工廠...
and we make 'em...
很丑陋
in an ugly factory.
他說我們的管理層都是王八蛋
He said our executives are sons of whores.
說了我什么
About me?
他說您胖  先生
He called you fat, sir.
頑固
Pigheaded.
繼續
Go on.
他說您不是亨利·福特
He said you're not Henry Ford.
您只是亨利·福特二世
You're Henry Ford II.
我要找到最好的工程師
I want the best engineers.
最好的車手
The best drivers.
我不在乎花費
I don't care what it costs.
我們要造一輛賽車
We're gonna build a race car.
我們要把那個
And we're gonna bury
渾身機油的意大利佬
that goddamn greasy wop
深埋在勒芒終點線的百尺之下
100 feet deep under the finish line at Le Mans.
我會親自到場見證這一幕的
And I will be there to watch it.
她們來了  快快快
Here they come. Go, go, go, go.
混蛋
Assholes.
你們太可悲了
You're really pathetic.
十分抱歉  美女們
I'm so sorry, girls.
查理
Charlie!
別成天沖著女孩子們扔爆竹了
Quit throwing crackers at the girls all damn day.
該死的
God damn it.
需要我去處理嗎
Do I gotta deal with this?
已經處理好了
It's already taken care of.
抱歉
Sorry about that.
沒錯  289立方英寸的V8發動機
So, yeah, 289 cubic inch V8.
牛逼
Far out.
大范圍地改造了AC Ace跑車的前段
Extensive rework of AC Ace's front end.
配有更強的后差速器來應付扭矩
And a stronger rear diff to handle the torque.
它在402米加速賽里表現如何
How's she handle a quarter mile?
我不是讓你去參加直線加速賽
Well, now, I'm not saying you should go drag racing,
但它跑402米用時13.6秒
but a quarter mile's 13.6.
沒錯
Yeah.
-這樣算快的嗎  -非常快了
- Is that good? - Oh, that's real good.
他這周之內把同一輛車賣了三遍了
He sold that same car three times this week.
-收現金嗎  現金可以嗎  -現金可以
- You take cash? Is cash okay? - Cash is okay.
沒錯  先生
Yeah, mister,
你剛給自己買了輛了不得的跑車
you just bought yourself one hell of a sport car.
好啊
All right.
你猜怎么著  我得...  菲爾
Tell you what, I'm gonna... Phil!
我讓我的同事來接待你
I'm gonna pass you off to my colleague here.
他會好好招呼你的
He gonna take care of you.
-菲爾  這位是懷亞特  -你好
- Phil, Wyatt. - Hello.
懷亞特  我把他借走一下
Wyatt, I'm gonna steal him for one second.
你來收錢
You take the payment.
無論你用什么方法  別讓他把車開走
Whatever you do, do not let him take that car.
那是杰夫·布利策的車
That's Jeff Blitzer's car.
也是弗蘭克·柯林斯和史蒂夫·麥奎恩的車
And Frank Collins' and Steve McQueen's.
該死  我忘了麥奎恩了
Shit. I forgot about McQueen.
早上好
Morning.
有什么事嗎
Can I help you?
卡羅爾·謝爾比
Carroll Shelby?
也許吧
Maybe.
李·艾亞科卡  福特汽車
Lee Iacocca, Ford Motor.
這個扳手有什么故事
What's with the wrench?
那個啊  說來話長了
That? Oh, long story.
我們這里越做越大了  李
We are just going from strength to strength here, Lee.
銷售額亮眼  賽道上成績斐然
Terrific sales, we're killing it on the track.
我知道上一批發動機的錢
Now, I know I owe Ford
我還沒給福特...
for that last batch of engines...
謝爾比先生  你放心
Mr. Shelby, I can assure you
我來這里不是為了
I'm not here for money
你欠福特的那些零部件的錢
that you might owe Ford for spare parts.
不是為這個
You're not?
不  不是的
No, I'm not.
好吧
Okay.
我是代表福特先生來的  亨利·福特二世
I'm here on behalf of Mr. Ford, Henry Ford II.
如果  假設一下
Suppose, um, hypothetically,
他希望他的公司
that he wanted his company
能贏得勒芒24小時耐力賽
to win the 24 Hours of Le Mans.
你是少數贏過的美國人
You're one of the only Americans that's ever done it...
所以我想知道
so I'm wondering...
要付出什么努力
what's it take?
假設嗎
Hypothetically?
假設
Hypothetically.
要付出的努力是錢買不到的
It takes something money can't buy.
錢可以買來速度
Money can buy speed.
但與速度無關  李
But it isn't about speed, Lee.
它不像其它的賽道
It's not just like those other tracks
只需要四個小時里不斷左轉
where all you do is turn to the left for four hours.
要想贏  需要一輛車
To win that race, you need a car
足夠輕  可以在直道上達到時速320公里
that's light enough to do 200 on the straightaways
足夠強  可以保持這個速度
but strong enough to keep that up
連續跑近五千公里
for 3,000 miles without a break.
需要的不僅是
Not just the best car
你們制造過的最好的車  還要
y'all have ever made, but better than anything
比恩佐·法拉利當年參賽的車更好
that Enzo Ferrari shows up with that year.
這還只是你的入場券
And that just gets you to the green flag.
接下來才是真正的問題
That's where your problems really start.
沒事吧
Is everything okay?
一邊去
Go away.
所以你覺得有難度
So you're saying it's challenging.
聽著  那都不算是賽道  李
Look, it's not even a track, Lee.
勒芒是13.7公里的鄉村道路
Le Mans is eight and a half miles of country road.
狹窄崎嶇  很難開
It's narrow, ungraded, it's rough.
轉彎處沒有預拱度  也沒有欄桿
There's no camber on the turns, no rails.
要開24小時
You gotta do that for 24 hours.
24小時啊  李
Twenty-four hours, Lee.
也就是說包括夜晚
That means night.
有一半的時間是夜里  屁都看不清
Half that race is in the dark. You can't see shit.
時不時有車不知道從哪竄出來
Cars coming up on you out of nowhere.
車手在賽道上出事  鮮血如注
Drivers stumbling around the track, pouring blood.
或許其中就有你的朋友  或許...
Maybe one of 'em is your friend. Maybe...
或許他身上會著火
Maybe he's on fire.
你筋疲力盡  饑腸轆轆
You're exhausted, you're hungry...
記不清自己的名字  忘記自己在哪
can't remember your name, what country you're in.
突然  你意識到自己正在直道上時速319公里
And all of a sudden, you realize you're doing 198 on a straight.
一旦有差錯
And if anything goes wrong...
一個墊圈壞掉  只值五美分的墊圈
you blow a gasket, a five-cent washer...
那就完了  都結束了
that's it, whole thing's over.
法拉利又贏了
Ferrari wins again.
就像去年和前年一樣
Just like he won last year and the year before that.
還有大前年
And the year before that.
沒錯
Yeah.
有難度
It's challenging.
所以你覺得
So you don't think...
福特汽車公司無法造出
that Ford Motor Company can build
有史以來最棒的賽車
the greatest race car the world's ever seen?
你覺得我們無法
You think that we are incapable
贏得這樣的比賽
of winning an event like that?
即使我們有厲害的合伙人
Even if we had a brilliant partner?
即使我們有不設上限的預算
Even if we wrote a, uh, blank check?
我說的是  你買不來冠軍  李
What I'm saying is, you can't buy a win, Lee.
但或許你可以買來有機會奪冠的人
But maybe you could buy the guy who gets you a shot.
修車店
換新的變速器  輪軸和減震器
A new transmission, axles, shocks all around,
把車身和輪胎都丟掉  這才有競爭力
ditch the body and the tires, you have yourself a contender.
這寶貝里面還有正常的東西嗎
Anything on this beauty that does work?
后視鏡挺不錯的
The mirrors are outstanding.
我走過來的時候就發現了
I saw that walking up.
所以你是晚上遛彎路過嗎
So, what, you just passing on an evening stroll?
斗牛犬  其實我有一份工作給你
Actually, Bulldog, I have a proposition for you.
你要造一輛能擊敗法拉利老爺子的車
You're gonna build a car to beat Old Man Ferrari...
-對  -和福特合作
- Yeah. - ...with Ford?
用福特的車
With a Ford?
沒錯
Correct.
你告訴他們需要多長時間
And how long did you tell them that you needed?
兩三百年嗎
Two, three hundred years?
九十天
Ninety days.
好吧  我們來梳理一下
All right, so let's just look at this for a moment.
為了論證
And for argument's sake,
我們先不提九十天這事
let's just forget about the whole 90-day thing.
所以先假設錢和時間
So let's just pretend you've got all the money in the world
都應有盡有
and all the time in the world.
-我喜歡這個開頭  -好吧
- I like the sound of that. - All right.
那
So...
你覺得福特會讓你
you think that Ford are gonna let you build
按你的想法
the car that you want...
去造你想要的車嗎
the way you want it?
那個福特汽車公司
The Ford Motor Company?
那些人
Those guys?
你去過底特律嗎
Have you ever been to Detroit?
他們有好幾層都是律師
They have floors and floors of lawyers
有成千上萬的營銷人員
and millions of marketing guys,
他們都要和你見面
and they're all gonna want to meet you.
他們都要和偉大的卡羅爾·謝爾比
They're gonna want to get their photo taken
一起合影
with the great Carroll Shelby,
他們會拍你馬屁
and they're gonna kiss your ass
然后回到他們溫馨的辦公室里
and go back to their lovely offices...
想出新的辦法來搞你
and they're gonna work out new ways to screw you.
為什么  因為他們不由自主
Why? Because they can't help it.
因為他們想要讓老板高興
Because they just want to please their boss
而他們的老板想要讓自己的老板高興  依次類推
who wants please his boss who wants to please his boss.
他們為此而厭惡自己
And they hate themselves for it.
但在心底里
But deep down...
他們更厭惡的
who they hate even more
是你這樣的人
are guys like you,
因為你與他們不同
because you're not like them,
因為你與他們思考的方式不同
because you don't think like them,
因為你不一樣
because you're different.
這是大魔王的意思
It's coming straight from the Deuce.
亨利·福特二世綽號"漢克大魔王"
他是認真的
He's serious.
他們會真金白銀地支持
They're gonna put real money behind it.
我敢說是的
I'll bet they are.
你知道為什么嗎
You know why?
因為有人  我沒說是誰
Because someone, and I'm not saying who,
有人告訴他們這是可能做成的
someone has told them that this is actually possible.
聽我說
Look...
這周日在科洛弗
this Sunday at Cloverfield,
他們會發布新的野馬汽車
they're launching the new Mustang.
并宣布賽車項目
They're gonna announce the race program.
來看看吧
Just come on by.
來看看  聽聽我的演講
Come take a look. Listen to my speech.
我會發表演講
I'm making a speech.
帶彼得來吧  他會喜歡的
Bring Peter. He'll love it.
好吧  謝爾
All right, Shel.
周日見
See you Sunday.
爸爸  看啊
Dad, look at that.
野馬
福特野馬  你覺得怎么樣
The Ford Mustang. What do you think?
我覺得這是秘書開的車
I think it's a secretary's car.
我喜歡
I like it.
抱...抱歉
Excu... Excuse me.
請你  請你不要那么做
Would you, would you not do that?
對不起
Sorry.
他是  他是你兒子嗎
Is this, is this your son?
是的
Yes, it is.
能請你讓他別碰車嗎
Would you ask him to keep his hands off the paintwork?
沒事  沒事  彼得
No, no, no, Peter.
沒關系  你是誰
You're okay. Who are you?
里奧·畢比  福特汽車公司的高級執行副總裁
Leo Beebe, Senior Executive Vice President, Ford Motor Company.
我負責野馬的發布
I'm responsible for the launch of the Mustang.
至少我們知道這是誰的責任了
At least now we know who's responsible.
別理解錯了  萊尼
Don't get me wrong, Lenny.
-是里奧  -車看起來很不錯
- Leo. - It looks fantastic.
但內部太繁瑣了
But inside, it's a lump of lard
花里胡哨的  糊弄普通人
dressed up to fool the public.
我的建議是
My advice is,
縮減直列六缸發動機和白癡的三檔加速
lose the inline-six and that idiotic three-speed,
縮短軸距  就能減輕半噸重量
shorten the wheelbase, somehow lose half a ton,
還能降低成本
and lower the price.
爸爸
Dad.
但就算是那樣
But even then,
我也更愿意買雪佛蘭
I'd still choose a Chevy Chevelle.
而那輛車可是爛得不行
And that's a fucking terrible car.
怎么樣了  史蒂夫
How are we doing up there, Steve?
科洛弗到了  謝爾比先生
There's Cloverfield, Mr. Shelby.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
介意我試一試著陸嗎
You mind if I take a shot at the landing?
不不不  我沒開玩笑
No, no, no. I mean it.
我1944年在圣安東尼奧開過B29轟炸機
I flew B-29s out of San Antone in '44.
你在開玩笑吧
You're kidding.
-沒騙你  -好吧
- I did. - Okay.
卡羅爾  你做什么呢
Carroll, what are you doing?
-他會開飛機嗎  -卡羅爾
- Does he know how to fly? - Carroll.
我以前有位指導員告訴我...
I had an instructor tell me, he said...
唐  我看現在最好系好安全帶
Don, I would say it's probably a good time to buckle up.
"為了大家好  別上天了"
"...do everybody a favor, stay on the ground."
我說真的
That's a true story.
-不  -該死
- Oh, no. - Oh, shit.
-該死的  -開始了
- God damn it. - Here we go.
野馬
這是一輛
This is the car
你想不到會出自底特律的車
you never expected from Detroit.
好了  走吧
All right. Let's go.
不留下來嗎  肯
Not staying, Ken?
都他媽是沖動消費  對吧
Ah, it's a bloody pig in a poke, isn't it?
他們來了
Here they come now.
-等等  他們要墜毀了嗎  -我的天
- Wait. Are they crashing? - Oh, Lord.
飛行員是誰
Who's the pilot?
要我猜的話  彼得
My guess, Peter...
是我們認識的人
it's someone we know.
一切都還好嗎
Everything all right up there?
不
Oh, no.
-不  -坐好了
- No! - Hang on.
該死  該死  該死
Oh, shit. Shit. Shit. Shit.
Shit. Shit. Shit.
知道嗎  就像騎自行車一樣
Tell you what, that's like riding a bike.
這出場的仗勢真不小
Talk about making an entrance.
-謝爾比  -我的天
- Shelby... - Good grief.
-謝爾比  -好了
- Shelby! - All right!
-看這里  看這里  -謝爾比
- Over here. Over here! - Shelby!
你們好啊
How y'all doing?
能給我簽個名嗎
Can I get your autograph, please?
能給我簽個名嗎  先生
Can I get your autograph, sir?
卡羅爾  這是羅伊·朗恩
Carroll, this is Roy Lunn.
老羅伊是來這里研發
Old Roy here is developing
英國設計的原型
the prototype over in England.
我認識羅伊  幸會  羅伊
Oh, hell, I know Roy. Good to see you, Roy.
歡迎來到瘋人院  謝爾比
Welcome to the madhouse, Shelby.
福特出動了整個管理層
Ford wheeled out the entire executive committee
來參加這一盛會
for this one.
稍等一下
Hold that thought.
你好  飛行家先生
Hello, Mr. Lindbergh.
你喜歡嗎  彼得  你好
You like that? Hey, Peter, how you doing?
-謝爾比先生  -很高興見到你
- Mr. Shelby. - Good to see you.
你要造一輛打敗法拉利的車嗎
Are you building a car that's gonna beat Ferrari?
我們要參加勒芒耐力賽  這是肯定的
Well, we're gonna go to Le Mans, that's for sure.
如果我們先沖過了終點線  那就會贏
And if we get across that finish line first, we're gonna win.
卡羅爾  我向你介紹里奧·畢比
Carroll, allow me to introduce Leo Beebe,
福特汽車的高級副總裁
Senior Vce President, Ford Motor.
好的  幸會  畢比先生
Oh, sure. Yeah. A pleasure, Mr. Beebe.
-感謝你光臨  -認識一下肯·邁爾斯
- Thank you for coming. - Say hello to Ken Miles
-和他兒子彼得吧  -好
- and his son, Peter. - Yeah.
-我們...我們見過了  -我們...我們見過了
- We've, um... we met. - We, uh... we met.
是啊
Yeah.
不是嗎
Didn't we?
所以...
So, um, well...
我帶彼得去衛生間
I'll take Petey for some pop.
祝你和這些人相處愉快  謝爾
Good luck with these guys, Shel.
-再見  謝爾比先生  -再見  彼得
- Bye, Mr. Shelby. - See you, Pete.
別擔心  他會留下來的
Don't worry, he's gonna stay.
你們倆在飛機上有聊幾句嗎
So, you two get a chance to talk on the plane?
有
Yeah. Uh...
卡羅爾  我們借一步說話
Carroll, why don't we just step this way for a second?
這是慣例  走個過場
Look, it's pro forma. It's window dressing.
但在你得表現得有來有往
But there's gotta be a sense of give-and-take
和那些...
between you and...
你懂的
you know.
我不懂
No, I don't.
團隊
The group.
The group?
高級創意總監們  卡羅爾
Senior creatives, Carroll.
就是為了讓大家都自在些
Just to make sure everybody's comfortable.
我很困惑  李
Well, I'm confused, Lee.
因為直到這一刻  直到剛剛
'Cause up until this moment, right now,
我都還挺自在的
I was comfortable.
你應該往外看看  卡羅爾
You should take a look out there, Carroll.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
你知道我看到了什么嗎
You know what I see?
我看到了一個機器
I see a machine.
我看到了一萬個活動的零件
I see 10,000 moving parts,
希望能夠和諧地運轉
moving hopefully in harmony,
而這也是我的職責
and it's my job to make it so.
指導你在其中和諧運轉是我的職責
It's my job to guide you through it.
我是來這里幫你的  卡羅爾
I am here to help you, Carroll.
但你得信任我
But you gotta trust me.
-失陪了  李  -卡羅爾
- Excuse me, Lee. - Carroll...
如果你不信任我  就不要走上臺
do not step on that stage if you don't trust me.
有請卡羅爾·謝爾比先生
Please welcome Mr. Carroll Shelby.
得走了
Gotta go.
-謝爾比  -謝爾比
- Shelby... - Oh. Shelby.
他說什么了
What'd he say?
他知道流程
He gets the drill.
福特野馬
謝謝
Thank you.
要是我爸今天在這里
Well, if my daddy was here today...
他會讓我坐下
he'd tell me to sit on down
讓那些大學生來負責滔滔不絕
and leave the yakking to the college boys...
所以  就像我開車一樣  我會盡快講完
so, like my cars, I'll make this fast.
我十歲時  爸爸告訴我"兒子...
When I was 10 years old, Pops said to me, "Son...
清楚自己想做什么的人是很幸運的
It's a truly lucky man who knows what he wants to do in this world.
因為他這輩子做事都會樂在其中"
"'Cause that man will never work a day in his life."
但也有一小撮人  珍貴的一小撮人
But there are a few, a precious few,
我不知道他們幸運與否
and, hell, I don't know if they're lucky or not.
但有一小撮人
But there are a few people
找到了自己必須要做的事
who find something they have to do.
他們為之沉迷的事
Something obsesses 'em.
如果不去做那件事
Something that if they can't do it,
他們就會被逼瘋
it's gonna drive them clean out of their mind.
我就是那種人
I'm that guy.
我知道還有一個人也有同感
And I know one other man feels exactly the same.
他就是...
His name...
他就是亨利·福特先生
His name is Mr. Henry Ford.
并且我們會一起
And together, we're gonna build
制造出世界上速度最快的汽車
the fastest automobiles in the world.
我們也會在勒芒耐力賽中創造歷史
And we're gonna make history, too, at Le Mans.
-我們走  -什么
- Let's go. - What?
我叫卡羅爾·謝爾比
My name is Carroll Shelby.
我制造賽車
I build race cars.
不  不管是什么  都不要
No. Whatever it is, no.
不
No.
三十分鐘
Thirty minutes.
我很累
Ah, just... I'm spent.
-我想洗個澡  - 你會想看看這個的
- I wanna have a bath. - You're gonna wanna see this.
相信我
Trust me.
三十分鐘  然后送你回來吃肉汁烘肉卷
Thirty minutes. I'll have you back for meatloaf and gravy.
三十分鐘
Thirty minutes.
對
Yeah.
謝爾比美國公司
見鬼
Bloody hell.
剛從英國空運過來
Fresh off the plane from England.
它還沒有完全調配好
Now, she's still a little on the rare side of cooked.
來吧
Come on.
有意思
Interesting.
怎樣
Well?
很糟糕
It's awful.
比糟糕還要糟
It's worse than awful.
這車抓地力太差
Yeah, it doesn't track.
三檔太高了
You know, the third gear is too high.
扭矩碰不到路面
Torque is not reaching the road.
因為前端太輕  轉向裝置不敏感
Steering's loose because the front end gets light.
并且速度超過225公里  它就成了...
And over 140, it thinks it's a...
飛機
Airplane.
對
Yeah.
它想起飛去夏威夷
It wants to lift off and fly to Hawaii.
還有嗎
Anything else?
等一下
One sec.
你昨晚回來很晚
You were back late last night.
對
Yeah.
你是在工作嗎
Were you working?
你沒去別的地方
So, you didn't go anyplace?
什么
What?
我是問  你昨晚沒去其它地方嗎
Well, I'm asking, did you go anyplace last night?
莫莉
Mollie.
這是個簡單的問題
It's a simple question.
我也回答了  不是嗎
And I answered, didn't I?
回答是什么
What was the answer?
出了什么事嗎  親愛的
Is something up, love?
你在做什么  你在做什么
What are you doing? What are you doing?
你開得特別快
You're driving very fast.
是嗎  是嗎
Oh, am I? Am I?
你就是
Yes, you are.
見鬼  你這是...這是做什么
Bloody hell! What are you... the hell is this?
你告訴我  因為我不知道
Well, you tell me, 'cause I don't know.
行  開慢點
Right, slow down!
莫莉
Mollie!
請你開慢點  好嗎
Please slow it down, all right?
你想殺了我們還是怎樣
You trying to kill us or something?
-我還以為我們喜歡這樣呢  -什么
- Well, I thought we love this shit. - What?
-見鬼  -這就是賽車的快感  不是嗎
- Bloody hell! - It's a bit of racing fun. No?
不不不  完全不一樣
No, no, no. It's not the same at all.
我還以為很刺激呢
Well, I think it's thrilling!
行
All right.
我看到你了  行嗎
Look, I saw you, all right?
我看見你和謝爾比一起離開  我看到你回來
I saw you leaving with Shelby, and I saw you coming back.
好  見鬼  行  你慢點
Okay. Shit. Okay, but slow it...
然后你就保持這種傻乎乎的表情一整天了
And then all day you've got that stupid look on your face.
莫莉  開慢點  你離得太近了
Mollie, slow down. You're too close here.
莫莉  趕緊踩剎車
Mollie, put on the brakes right now...
你不告訴我出了什么事  我就不停
Not until you tell me what's going on!
行  我去看了一輛車
All right. I went to look at a car.
-和謝爾比一起  -和謝爾比一起
- With Shelby? - With Shelby.
-一輛賽車  -差不多吧
- A racing car? - Sort of.
要轉彎了  你最好抓緊點
There's a corner coming. You'd better hold on.
你準備一直踩著油門嗎
Are you gonna lift your foot off at all through this?
對  因為我喜歡干凈利落的比賽路線
No, 'cause I like a clean racing line.
慢點
Slow down!
好吧
Okay.
謝爾給了我一個工作
Shel offered me a job.
福特有一輛想用來和法拉利比賽的車
Ford has a car that they want to put up against a Ferrari.
-你告訴我你不干了  -就是這樣  現在慢點
You told me you were done. That's it. Now, slow...
我沒同意
I didn't say yes.
慢點
Slow down.
你告訴我你不干了
You told me you quit.
-我不懂  -養老享福  你說的
- I don't understand. - Get fat and old, you said.
養老享福
Fat and old.
-我不懂  -你是那么告訴我的
- I don't understand. - That's what you told me.
我不懂
I don't understand.
你生氣是因為我說我不干了
Are you upset because I said I was done
還是因為我看了一輛賽車
or because I looked at a race car?
別對我說謊  肯
Just don't lie to me, Ken.
別因為你覺得我會高興
Don't make it a secret,
就對你想要什么
what you want or what you feel,
你感覺如何  藏著掖著
just because you think it's gonna make me happy.
莫  我都不知道我是什么感覺
Moll, I don't even know what I feel.
如果你要參賽
If you do this...
那他這次最好給你錢
then he better be paying you this time.
因為我增加工作時間就沒法照顧彼得
'Cause I can't work any more hours and look after Peter.
國稅局已經封了修車店
You know, the IRS have the garage.
我不要再失去我的家
I'm not losing my home.
一天兩百塊
It's 200 a day.
還報銷開支
Plus expenses.
你在跟我開玩笑嗎
Are you shitting me?
但我還沒有決定
But I haven't decided.
一天兩百美金
$200 a day?
你瘋了嗎
Are you nuts?
柳泉賽道
看看這個  太離譜了  這里
Look at this. This is ridiculous. Here.
謝爾  它吸氣
So, Shel, grabbing air.
這就是問題
That's the problem.
速度超過145公里  空氣就只進不出
Over 90, air's getting in, not getting out.
問題在車頭  我開的時候感覺到了
It's the nose, I can feel it in the wheel.
邁爾斯先生  如果有問題
Mr. Miles, if there's a problem,
電腦會發現的
the computer will find it.
行  查理
All right. Charlie,
去拿點膠帶和毛線
get some Scotch tape and a ball of wool.
好了  很好
All right. Good, good, good.
現在我們把這些垃圾拆掉
So, now let's just, uh, get all of this junk out.
對嗎  老爹
Right, Pops?
對對  我同意
Yeah, yeah. I concur.
來吧  伙計們
Come on, guys.
他們在做什么
What are they doing?
讓你的車跑得更快些
Making your car faster.
這里  就這里
There. Right there.
氣流開始堵塞了
Airflow's getting stuck.
我看到了  毛線直直往上飄
I see it. Yarn blows straight up.
-對  -前面在飄高
- Yep. - The front's lifting.
見鬼  他說得對
Damn, he's right.
這輛車想變得更快  我能感覺出來
This car wants to go faster. I feel it.
再輕點就會變得脆弱
Any lighter, we're getting fragile.
上星期它已經減重了三十公斤
Took 70 pounds out of her in the last week.
通過這次改裝  它已經輸出了最大馬力了
She's outputting max horsepower from this displacement.
那就換個更大的發動機
So put in a bigger engine.
我們要把發動機放在哪  車頂嗎
Where we gonna put it? On the roof?
設法讓它比納斯卡車賽標準
Managed to make it 52 pounds lighter
輕了二十三公斤
than the NASCAR unit.
全新的鋁制缸蓋
All-new aluminum cylinder heads...
減振器  水泵  更小的閥門
vibration dampeners, water pump, smaller valves.
我們稱之為野獸
We call it the Beast.
我能看出原因
Yeah, I can see why,
但不改裝機座的話
but how's it gonna fit
要怎么把它塞進去
without a redesign of the engine bed?
那肯定不容易
Well, it certainly wasn't easy.
早安  先生們  謝爾比先生
Good morning, gentlemen. Mr. Shelby.
你們已經把那個裝進了一臺GT40嗎
So, you already put that in a GT40?
恐怕確實如此
I'm afraid we have.
真想不到
I'll be damned.
當然  那很重
Well, it's heavy, of course.
控制起來有點困難  特別是剎車
Problems with the handling, especially the stopping.
-我能給你看數據  -有什么問題
- I can show you the data. - What problems?
轉向有點失靈  但是...
Understeers a little, but...
我能借用一下那個嗎
Can I borrow that?
就一下  謝謝
Just a second. Thank you.
肯
Ken!
肯  你在測試前要不要先和總部協商一下
Ken, perhaps you want to check with HQ before you test...
他說什么
What did he say?
我們得問問...
We should ask...
好吧
Right.
太棒了
Oh, yes!
謝爾比先生  歡迎來到迪爾伯恩
Mr. Shelby, welcome to Dearborn.
你怎么想到來看試車
What are you doing at a test track?
你的漂亮西裝會沾上嘉實多汽油的
You're gonna get Castrol oil all over that nice suit.
我想聽聽你對一些計劃中的決策有什么意見
I wanted to hear your thoughts on a few planning decisions.
關于勒芒耐力賽的參賽人員
You know, personnel for Le Mans.
我們陣容強大
Well, it's a hell of a lineup.
肯·邁爾斯  菲爾·希爾
Ken Miles, Phil Hill,
克里斯·阿蒙  布魯斯·邁凱輪
Chris Amon, Bruce McLaren.
希爾去定了  阿蒙和邁凱輪也是
Hill's a lock. Amon, McLaren, too.
我們對邁爾斯參賽不太確定
We're less sure about Miles.
我們喜歡里奇·金瑟爾
We like Richie Ginther...
馬斯滕·格里高利  鮑勃·邦杜蘭特
Masten Gregory, Bob Bondurant.
你們想要最好的車手
Well, you're gonna want the best driver for the car.
懂車的車手
Understands the machine.
肯就是最佳人選
That's Ken.
太棒了
Oh! Yes!
再給點勁  快  再給點勁  寶貝
More of that, please. More of that, my girl.
你或許比我更懂賽車  謝爾比先生
I may not get the finer points of racing, Mr. Shelby,
但我懂人
but I do know people.
邁爾斯是...
Miles is a...
他屬于"垮掉的一代"  從穿著看得出來
Well, he's a beatnik. He dresses like one.
福特象征著可靠
Ford means reliability.
肯·邁爾斯無法代表福特的形象
Ken Miles is not a Ford man.
加把勁  加把勁
Giddy-up! Giddy-up!
目前圈速紀錄是多少  伯特
What's the lap record here, Burt?
1分58秒
1:58.
他跑了1分50秒
1:50 dead.
"垮掉的一代"
A beatnik?
那個男人在諾曼底登陸戰役中
That man landed a busted tank
開著一架故障坦克登陸沙灘
on the beach at D-Day
然后順利地橫穿歐洲開到柏林
and drove it clean across Europe to Berlin.
這哪算"垮掉的一代"
A beatnik?
李不久前問我
You know, Lee here asked me a while back,
"錢買不到的那樣東西是什么"
"What's the one thing money can't buy?"
我告訴你答案
I'll tell you what it is.
是把握方向盤的那個純粹的賽車手
A pure racer behind the wheel of your car.
肯·邁爾斯便是
That's Ken Miles.
話雖如此
Well, be that as it may...
我們覺得他有點太純粹了
we think he may be too pure.
卡羅爾  要顧全大局
Carroll, do not lose sight of the big picture here.
"太純粹了"
"Too pure"?
這是什么意思
What exactly does that mean?
意思是他太自我了
It means he's all about himself.
美國廣播公司采訪他的時候
ABC puts a microphone under his nose,
或許會有他不喜歡的細節
perhaps there's a detail he dislikes,
屆時有幾百萬觀眾...
millions watching...
你確定他不會亂說話嗎
do you trust him not to put out the wrong message?
你們可以找個外表光鮮
Well, look, you can get a clean-cut,
上鏡的典型美國小子
all-American poster boy
讓他坐上賽車
and stick him behind the wheel,
教他怎么說話
teach him what to say.
你們不如讓多麗絲·戴參賽吧
Shit, you get Doris Day to drive the car,
美國二戰后著名歌手
如果你們想輸的話
if all you want to do is lose.
所以你在這件事上有不同意見
So, you don't agree with us on this issue?
我是說你得相信我的選人眼光
I'm saying you gotta trust me on this one.
卡羅爾  考慮到營銷因素
Carroll, with marketing concerns,
這不可能
that's just not possible.
選一個福特類型的車手開著福特車參賽
Put a Ford-type driver in a Ford car,
謝爾比先生
Mr. Shelby.
這是福特的做事方式
That's the Ford way.
法拉利又贏下了一場錦標賽
Yet another championship win for Ferrari
英國賽車手約翰·瑟蒂斯
as British driver John Surtees
開著法拉利312...
pilots his Ferrari 312...
法拉利贏了
Ferrari wins.
這是瑟蒂斯自1964年以來的首場勝利...
It's Surtees' first win since the '64...
楔木  我們有楔木了
Wedges. We have wedges.
很好  很好
Oh, good, good, good.
完美
Perfect.
-一米嗎  -對
- 40? - Yep.
-你好  老板  -你好  丹
- Hey, boss. - Hey, Dan.
老板  法拉利剛剛拿下了...
Boss, Ferrari just bagged...
你有護照嗎
You got a passport?
那是什么
What's that?
簽字  申請一個護照
Sign that. Get a passport.
周五前交給我  弗羅斯特
Get it back to me by Friday. Frosty.
伙計們  我要去法國了
Boys, I'm going to France.
菲爾
Phil.
肯  能談談嗎
Ken, can I get a word?
我能留下這個嗎
Can I take this?
你知道為什么福特給車取名GT40嗎
Do you know why Ford named it the GT40?
為什么是"40"
Why they put that "40" on there?
-不知道  -這是規定  知道嗎
- No. - Regulations. All right?
車身要有40英寸[一米]高
We gotta be 40 inches high
才能滿足離地間隙要求
to make the ground clearance requirements.
不多不少
No more, no less.
他們在每場比賽前都會測量
They measure it before every race.
問題是這么高的車身
Problem is, that with that height,
車底阻力太大了  對吧
there's too much drag under the car, all right?
所以我們想了個辦法
So, we have a solution.
楔木  我們把楔木放在
Wedges. We put wedges
-懸掛上...  -你下周不能去
- in the suspension... - You're not coming next week.
你不能去  肯
You're not coming, Ken.
我們會帶上邁凱輪
We're taking McLaren,
克里斯·阿蒙  菲爾·希爾...
Chris Amon, Phil Hill...
還有鮑勃·邦杜蘭特
and Bob Bondurant.
這是福特的決定
It's Ford's call.
他們認為你形象欠佳
It is their opinion that you are not a good image,
所以你不能開福特賽車
so you cannot drive their race car.
即使是你盡心盡力把賽車
And putting aside the fact that you made that car
改造成現在這樣...
whatever the hell it is...
而且你是我眼中最棒的賽車手
and you're the best man I got behind the wheel...
我會調整供油管路
I'm gonna reroute the oil line.
要是發生泄漏  汽油會滴到
If there's spillage, it could drip
-制動盤的左后方  -肯...
- onto the rear nearside disc. - Ken...
告訴那些小子們
Tell the boys
全程注意車速
to watch their pace come sunrise.
變速箱會過熱
The, uh, the gearbox will overheat.
環球航空公司
謝爾比美國公司
肯  比賽快開始了
Ken, the race is starting soon.
要打開收音機嗎
Want it on the radio?
不了  除非你想聽
Not unless you do.
比賽
...of the race.
他們來了
There they are.
瑪莎拉蒂進入了埃索斯連續彎
The Maserati going into the Esses,
但依然是2號車
but it's still the number 2 car,
由克里斯·阿蒙駕駛
driven by Chris Amon.
第三名是布魯斯·邁凱輪駕駛的福特1號
In third place is the number 1 Ford that is driven by Bruce McLaren.
福特GT啟動速度尤為驚人
A tremendously fast start for the Ford GT.
福特2號圈速3分43秒4
3:43.4 lap for car number 2, a Ford.
我認為在比賽的這個階段速度有點太快了
I think it's a little bit quick for this stage of the game.
現在有點開太快了
Little bit quick right now.
開得太急了
Racing too hot.
這能持續到最后大概一小時  你不覺得嗎
This could go down to the last hour or so, don't you think?
或許可以  但是
It could, but the probabilities
在24小時耐力賽里
for a finish like that
出現這種終場的可能性極小
in a 24-hour race are awfully small.
又一輛福特進入了維修站
Another Ford has come into the pits.
修理工把車推進了
It's being pushed into the pits
-維修站  -汽缸墊
- by the mechanics. - Head gasket.
賽車不是航天火箭
The car's not a moon rocket.
七號車緊隨鮑勃·邦杜蘭特  位居第四
Trailing Bob Bondurant in fourth, car number 7.
隨后是邁克爾·帕克斯駕駛的法拉利20號
Leading number 20, Ferrari. Michael Parkes.
所以目前福特包攬前三名  你怎么看
So, we have Ford running one, two, three. How about that?
太快了  絕對太快了
Too soon. Surely too soon.
維修工真的非常值得尊重...
One has to really be respectful of the mechanism with any...
有條大新聞
Here's the big story,
先前處于領先地位的里奇·金瑟爾駕駛的福特
the lead Ford, driven by Richie Ginther,
由于變速箱故障退出了  最新的領先者是...
retired with gearbox trouble, and the new leader...
變速箱  我告訴過他們  一定要小心
Gearbox. I told them. Be gentle with it.
和他的搭檔洛倫佐·班迪尼
...and his partner Lorenzo Bandini...
他是去年獲獎車手之一
...who was one of the winning drivers last year.
是誰
Who's there?
我們又回來了
Again, we're back,
為您實時轉播法國的勒芒賽事
speaking to you live from Le Mans, France.
勒芒24小時耐力賽  第33屆國際汽車
The 24 Hours of Le Mans, the Grand Prix of Endurance,
耐力大獎賽
the 33rd renewal.
你在聽什么廣播
What's that you're listening to?
法國的一場比賽
Oh, some race over in France.
很精彩嗎
Exciting?
我沒怎么聽
I'm not really paying much attention.
然而  菲爾  回首1933年
However, Phil, there was one time in 1933,
領先者變化了三次
when the lead changed hands three times.
♪ I ain't lyin' ♪
I Put a Spell on You - Nina Simone
♪ No, I ain't lyin' ♪
這不算是香檳...
It's not exactly champagne...
♪ You know I can't stand it... ♪
但至少也有氣泡
but it's got bubbles.
♪ You know better, daddy ♪
♪ I can't stand it 'cause you put me down ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I put a spell on you ♪
♪ Because you're mine ♪
♪ You're mine ♪
謝謝  莫莉
Thanks, Mollie.
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
福特汽車公司
底特律獨立報
福特慘敗
福特和法拉利之間是有區別的
There's a difference between Ford and Ferrari...
格蕾絲
Grace.
好的  先生  我馬上帶他進來
Yes, sir. I will send him right in.
行政前臺
謝謝
Thank you.
謝爾比先生  福特先生現在可以見你了
Mr. Shelby, Mr. Ford will see you now.
-好  -你還愿意
- All right. - Are you still willing
賭上名譽相信這個人嗎
to stake your reputation on this guy?
這邊請  謝爾比先生
This way, Mr. Shelby.
福特先生
Mr. Ford.
各位
Gentlemen.
謝爾比
Shelby.
給我一個理由  說服我不解雇
Give me one reason why I don't fire everyone
由你牽頭的這一群殘兵敗將
associated with this abomination starting with you.
先生
Well, sir...
我坐在外面舒服的休息室里
I was thinking about that very question
就在想這個問題
as I sat out there in your lovely waiting room.
當我坐在那里
As I was sitting there...
我看見那個小小的紅色文件夾
I watched that little red folder right there...
四次經手...
go through four pairs of hands...
才到達您手里
before it got to you.
當然這還不包括
'Course that doesn't include...
文件送到十九樓之前
the 22 or so other Ford employees
很可能會接觸文件的
who probably poked at it
二十多位其他福特員工
before it made its way up to the 19th floor.
恕我直言  先生
All due respect, sir,
官僚主義是無法贏下比賽的
you can't win a race by committee.
您需要一個負責人
You need one man in charge.
依我之見  好消息是
Now, the good news, as I see it,
即使面臨這些重重困難
is that even with all the extra weight...
我們還是成功擺布了
we still managed to put old Mr. Ferrari
法拉利老頭
exactly where we want him.
是嗎
Did we?
是的
Oh, yes.
解釋一下
Expand.
這...
Well...
當然了  我們之前沒有...
sure, we hadn't...
我們還沒解決該如何過彎
We haven't worked out how to corner yet.
發動機過熱
Or stay cool.
抓地力也不足
Or stay on the ground.
而且很多零件都壞了
And a lot of stuff broke.
事實上  唯一沒壞的地方是剎車
In fact, the only thing that didn't break was the brakes.
而且說白了  我們都沒辦法打包票
Hell, right now, we don't even know
車漆能不能撐24小時不掉色
if our paint job will last the whole 24 hours.
但最后一圈
But our last lap...
我們在慕尚直道上跑出了350公里的時速
we clocked 218 miles an hour down the Mulsanne Straight.
雖然恩佐老頭有多年賽車經歷
Now, in all his years of racing...
他也沒見過能跑這么快的車
old Enzo ain't never seen anything move that fast.
現在他明白了
And now he knows...
毫無疑問
without a doubt...
我們的車要比他的快
we're faster than he is...
哪怕是我們派錯了車手上場
even with the wrong driver...
還存在官僚主義
and all the committees.
他此時此刻
And that's what he's thinking about
坐在意大利摩德納想的就是這件事
while he's sitting in Modena, Italy... right now.
那家伙現在嚇壞了
That man is scared to death...
他怕您今年會變得足夠明智
that this year you actually might be smart enough
開始信任我
to start trusting me.
沒錯
So, yeah...
您完全擺布了法拉利
I'd say you got Ferrari exactly where you want him.
不用謝
You're welcome.
過來
Come here.
看到那座小建筑了嗎
See that little building down there?
二戰期間
In World War II...
五分之三的美國轟炸機在那里生產
three out of five US bombers rolled off that line.
你以為打敗希特勒的是羅斯福嗎
You think Roosevelt beat Hitler?
再好好想想
Think again.
這不是福特汽車公司
This isn't the first time
第一次上歐洲戰場了
Ford Motor's gone to war in Europe.
我們會做的可不只是擺弄文件
We know how to do more than push paper.
這家公司只有一個老大
And there is one man running this company.
你直接向他匯報
You report to him.
明白了嗎
You understand me?
是  先生
Yes, sir.
去吧  卡羅爾  準備作戰
Go ahead, Carroll. Go to war.
謝謝您  先生
Thank you, sir.
你說得沒錯
You were right.
就是變速箱的問題
It's the gearbox.
我們開得太心急了
We ran too hot.
四個里面壞了三個
Three out of four of 'em broke.
拉桿也弄壞了另一個
The rod blew on the other one.
我們要重回賽場了  肯
We're going back, Ken.
他們說這次歸我全權負責
They told me I had "Carte blanche" this time.
我查了下  這是法語"胡說八道"的意思
I looked it up. It's French for "Horseshit."
我知道他們肯定還會想盡一切辦法
I know they're gonna squeeze our nuts any way they can
來打壓我們
soon as they work out how.
那個...
Well, the, uh...
我買的冰淇淋要化了
ice cream's melting.
好吧  肯
All right. Hey, Ken.
你是想讓我道歉嗎
You want me to apologize?
要我求你嗎
You want me to beg?
我也不知道  可以試試
I don't know. Let's try it out.
你先試了再說
Let's, uh, see how that feels.
肯  對不起
Ken, I'm sorry.
真心的
Sincerely.
你知道我為了能讓賽車上跑道
Do you have any idea the kind of shit that I had to eat
受了多少臉色嗎
just to get four wheels on that grid?
你不知道
No, you don't.
因為你完全不用為那些事操心
'Cause you don't deal with any of that stuff.
所以別磨嘰了  肯  我們還有正事要做
Now knock it off, Ken. We got work to do,
車又不是從天上掉下來的
and this car ain't gonna build itself.
好  行吧
Okay. All right.
天啊
God.
給我過來
Come here.
-你他媽就一賣車的  -媽的
- Bloody car salesman. - Shit!
來啊  吃我一記
Come on. Now you're gonna get it.
松手
Get off me!
固執的王八蛋
Stubborn son of a bitch.
天啊
God!
-看好了  -來啊
- You just look... - Right.
-怎么樣  -你...
- Yeah, now. - You...
你還好嗎
You all right?
媽的
Shit!
看我不收拾你
Now you're gonna get it.
給我過來
Come here.
完事
Done.
莫莉  親愛的
Mollie, darling.
怎么了  老公
Yes, love?
能給我拿瓶汽水嗎
Can I get a fizzy pop, please?
好的
Yes, love.
你要嗎  謝爾比
You want one, too, Shelby?
-別給他  -好  謝了莫莉
- No. No. - Uh, yes, please, Mollie.
別給他  他自己買去
No. He can get his own.
只給我拿就行了
Just for me, please.
上次干架是什么時候來著
How long has that been?
至少得有三四年了
Oh, it's gotta be three or four years, at least.
對  在加州河濱市
Right. Riverside.
嗯  美國賽車俱樂部區域錦標賽
Yeah. SCCA Divisional Championship.
你把我手指弄斷了
You broke my finger.
你抓著我手臂
What's that nippy bloody thing
扯奶頭那一招是什么來頭
you do under the arm, that thing?
我叫那招"羊駝咬奶"
Yeah. I call that the Llama Bite.
你還取了個名字
You name it?
你從哪學來的  女童子軍嗎
Where'd you learn that? The Girl Scouts?
-怎么  你想再試一次嗎  -給你
- What? You wanna go again? - Here you go.
你真好
You're an angel.
謝謝
Thank you.
不客氣
My pleasure.
好了  我準備去趟雜貨店
Right. Well, I'm about to go to the grocery store.
要給你們帶什么東西嗎
Anything you think you'll need?
冰淇淋
Um, ice cream.
冰淇淋就不錯  還要...
Ice cream would be good and, uh...
面包
bread.
好
Right.
我不用  謝謝
No, I'm good. Thank you.
謝謝  莫
Thanks, Moll.
你還吃這藥治心臟病呢
You still take those for your ticker?
我是因為好吃才吃的
Only 'cause they're so delicious.
-去你的  -滾吧
- Up yours. - Oh, go to hell.
跑起來  加把勁  加把勁
Come on. Giddy-up. Giddy-up. Giddy-up.
菲爾  這是你的  哥們
Phil! Here's the one for you, mate.
迪諾  過來
Dino, come here.
怎么樣
Well?
踩油門還是會有滯后感
There's still lag when I hit the gas.
把真空次級化油器換了吧
Let's get rid of the vacuum secondaries.
查理  拿霍利化油器來
Charlie, get a Holley carb.
我們要重新裝配油門總成
We're gonna rebuild the throttle assembly.
離迪通拿耐力賽只剩三周時間了
Three weeks to Daytona,
這車還是問題百出
and it still feels like a bag of squirrels.
剎車過熱
Brake heat.
那完全又是另一碼事了
That's a whole different ball game.
好了  彼得  來跟我溜一圈
All right, Petey, let's go for that ride.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
看到那條縫了嗎
You see that crack?
那是我過八號彎的記號
That's my marker for turn eight.
做什么的  提醒你減速嗎
What, to slow down?
輕踩剎車  換低檔
Brush the brakes and downshift.
但你到時候會跑到時速240多公里
But you'll be going 150 miles an hour.
沒錯
Yeah.
那你怎么看得見呢
So how do you see it?
速度是很快  但車在加速的時候
You're going fast, but as the car speeds up...
周圍的一切都會隨之變慢
everything else slows down.
不能這么看
You don't do that.
視線要開闊點  對嗎
You do this. Right?
這樣你就能看到一切
And then you see everything.
你還留了別的記號嗎
Do you set other markers?
那是當然
Indeed I do.
還留了很多
Lots of them.
知道了  因為我們不能
Yeah, 'cause you can't just
全程都把賽車逼得太緊  對嗎
push the car hard the whole way, right?
沒錯  你得善待賽車
That's right. You have to be kind to the car.
你會感覺到這個小可憐在你身下呻吟
You feel the poor thing groaning underneath you.
如果你想將一臺機器推向極致
If you're gonna push a piece of machinery to the limit
還指望著它不會散架
and expect it to hold together,
那你就得感覺到它的極限在哪里
you have to have some sense of where that limit is.
看前方
Look out there.
那就是完美的一圈
Out there is the perfect lap.
毫無差錯
No mistakes.
每次換檔  每次過彎
Every gear change, every corner...
都恰到好處
perfect.
你看到了嗎
You see it?
應該看到了
I think so.
很多人都看不到
Most people can't.
很多人甚至都不知道它的存在  但它就在那
Most people don't even know it's out there, but it is.
就在眼前
It's there.
你想吃冰淇淋嗎
You want some ice cream?
-好啊  -行
- Yeah. - All right.
我們走
Come on, then.
你知道這是什么記號嗎
Do you know what this marker is?
-什么  -那個
- What? - That one.
扯我手指  你就知道了
Pull my finger. You'll find out.
他還要多久才進站
How much longer before he comes in?
我們每四個小時換一次車手
Uh, well, we change drivers every four hours,
-大概還要十分鐘  -不  等等
- so about 10 minutes. - No, hang on.
你的意思是現在由畢比全權負責了
You're saying Beebe is 100 percent in charge now?
沒錯  他想讓邁爾斯走人
Yes, and he wants Miles gone.
聽著  他擺明了是在針對他
Look, it's personal with this guy.
而且他確實有和你對著干的資本
And, yes, he has the leverage to stick it to you.
他和大魔王明天就坐飛機過去
He and the Deuce are flying there tomorrow.
他到時候會當面告訴你
He's gonna tell you in person.
他現在就等著你失控發飆了
Now, all he is hoping for is that you lose your cool.
是時候妥協了
It's time to let this go.
你不能葬送全局
You cannot destroy the whole thing.
不能為了這區區一個人
Not for one goddamn guy.
-我當然可以  -有什么必要呢
- Sure, I can. - Well, why?
因為在我們說話這會
'Cause while we're here talking,
他正在外頭做實事
he's out there getting it done.
糟了
Oh, shit!
他剎車失靈了
He's got brake fade.
慢點
Ease off!
卡羅爾
Carroll?
-快救他出來  -彼得
- Get him out! - Peter!
別站這  快進去
Go on. Go inside.
待在這里別動
Just stay there.
-快救肯  -肯
- Get Ken! - Ken!
快救他出來
Get him out!
他在這里
There he is!
肯
Ken!
我看到他了
I can see him.
-肯  -快點
- Ken! - Come on.
剎車
The brakes.
把這破發動機拆了行嗎
Let's just rip out the damn engine. All right?
無法制動的話要它有什么用
We can't use it if we can't stop.
我們要是悠著點開
You know, the brakes would last longer
剎車還是能撐一會的
if we slowed down a bit.
那不就違背要給車加動力的初衷了嗎
Wouldn't that defeat the whole purpose of the extra power?
我還以為我們在這里這么努力
You know, I thought the whole point
是為了拿下比賽呢
was to win the damned race.
要不我們重新設計總成
Maybe we could design a new assembly.
我們在進站時不要僅僅更換剎車片
Instead of swapping out the pads in the pits...
而是換掉整個剎車系統
swap out the entire braking system.
包括剎車盤
Rotors included.
換上一個新的
Put in a fresh one.
等等  等等  老爹
Wait, wait, wait, Pops,
我們能那么做嗎
are we allowed to do that?
不知道  我看不懂法語
I don't know. I don't read French.
勒芒24小時耐力賽
賽車場指南
剎車也是"一種零件"  對吧
Well, brakes are "a part" like any other, right?
我們可以換零件
We are allowed to change parts.
沒錯  但有時間換嗎
Yes. Will we have time to do that?
我還不知道  查理
I don't know yet, Charlie.
我要帶他回家了
I'm gonna take him home.
好
All right.
解決這破事
Sort this shit out.
我會的
I will.
你身上著過火嗎
Have you ever been on fire?
沒有  我沒遇到過這種情況
Well, no, it's never happened to me.
不過賽車服是防火的  知道嗎
But the suit's flameproof, see?
它能隔熱
It keeps heat out.
好吧
Yeah.
但路易斯-埃文斯在摩洛哥大獎賽中被燒死
But Lewis-Evans burned to death in the Moroccan Grand Prix.
他也穿了防火賽車服
He had a flameproof suit on.
沒錯  但是...
Yeah, but...
他被卡住了
See, he got stuck.
無法呼吸
He couldn't breathe.
只要人下了車  就沒事
So, as long as you get out of the car, you're okay.
爸爸下了車
Dad got out.
-確實  -彼得
- He sure did. - Peter!
再見
Bye.
See ya.
-你沒事吧  -沒事
- You all right? - Yeah.
你怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
別跟我說剎車
And don't be telling me brakes
或者我差點一命嗚呼什么的
or me almost kicking the bucket out there.
跟那些穿西裝的人有關  對吧
It's something to do with the suits, isn't it?
都在控制之中
It's under control.
怎么了
What is it?
我們說過你做好你的事
You know how we talked about how you do your thing,
我做好我的事
I do my thing?
-這是我的事  -說真的  謝爾...
- This is my thing. - Really, Shel...
相信我  肯
Just trust me, Ken.
你有計劃嗎
You got a plan?
必須的
Absolutely.
好計劃嗎
It a good one?
風險很高
It's high risk.
有多高
How high risk?
極其高
Extremely high risk.
了不起
Well, that's something.
-很高興我們談了  -隨時再聊
- Glad we had this talk. - Anytime.
福特先生  真是驚喜
Mr. Ford, this is a surprise.
抱歉擅自前來  謝爾比先生
Apologies for the unannounced intrusion, Mr. Shelby,
但是我付了九百萬造汽車
but when a man pays $9 million for an automobile,
起碼應該能看看長什么樣
he ought to at least be able to see it.
聽起來很合理
Well, that sounds reasonable enough.
謝爾比  能和你談一下嗎
Shelby, could I have a word?
當然
Sure.
-私下談嗎  -是的
- In private? - Yeah.
那樣更好
That would be preferable.
好吧  菲爾
All right. Hey, Phil.
你能招呼一下福特先生嗎
You wanna take care of Mr. Ford here?
福特先生  他是菲爾·雷明頓
Mr. Ford, that's Phil Remington.
當然
Of course.
來我辦公室  里奧
Come up to my office, Leo.
-幸會  先生  -菲爾
- Pleasure to meet you, sir. - Phil.
我帶您參觀一下您的車
Give you a little tour of your car.
我們拿掉了289小發動機
We took out your 289 small block...
換上了7L的427發動機
and put in a 427 7-liter.
首先  我想消除誤會
Firstly, I want to just clear the air.
希望我們之間的分歧
I hope that whatever disagreements between us
能歸結于...
can just be chalked up to...
激烈爭論時自然而然的血氣方剛
natural red-bloodedness in the heat of battle.
感謝你這么說  里奧  真的
I appreciate that, Leo. Truly, I do.
謝爾比  我有責任通知你
It falls on me, Shelby, to inform you that
我被任命為賽車項目的執行總監
I have been appointed overall executive director of the racing program.
我真心希望這不會成為我們之間的問題
Now, I do hope that this won't be a problem between us.
里奧  我向你保證  不會的
Well, I assure you, Leo, it will not.
卡羅爾
Carroll...
Carroll!
427發動機的最高速是多少
And what is that top speed with the 427?
不如我們開一圈
Well, why don't we take it for a spin?
-什么  -來吧  福特先生
- What? - Yeah, go on, Mr. Ford.
-上車  來吧  -你想讓我...
- Hop on in. Go on. - You want me to...
感覺一下九百萬的車是什么樣
Just see what $9 million feels like.
老天
God...
把門打開
Open the door!
你扶著我這里
Just hold me right there,
你抓住我的手
and you take my hand.
天啊  我坐到了蛋蛋
Oh, God. I sat on my nuts.
下一輛車我們會改進舒適感  別擔心
We're gonna build the next one for comfort. Don't you worry.
-打開門  -抱歉  先生  稍等一下
- Open the door. - Sorry, sir, if you just give me a moment.
-打開門  -這門不好開
- Open the door. - It's a sticky one.
準備好了嗎
You ready?
方向盤中間那名字應該能讓你知道
The name on the middle of that steering wheel should tell you
我生來就準備好了  謝爾比  出發
that I was born ready, Shelby. Hit it.
好樣的
Attaboy.
這車推背感挺強  是吧
It's got a little kick, doesn't it?
-打開門  -好了
- Open this door. - There we go.
天吶  畢比先生  你還好嗎
Good God, Mr. Beebe. You okay, sir?
天啊
Oh, my God!
天啊  天啊
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
棒極了
Yeah, baby.
差不多就是這會外行會嚇得尿褲子
It's about right now the uninitiated have a tendency to soil themselves.
天啊
Oh, my God!
福特先生
Mr. Ford...
您沒事吧
You okay?
福特先生
Mr. Ford...
您還好嗎
you all right?
真沒想到
I had no idea.
我真希望我爸爸
I wish my daddy...
能活著看到這個
he were alive to see this.
感受這個
To feel this.
這不是一臺隨便誰都能進來輕松掌控的車
Now, this is not a machine just anybody can get in and easily control.
絕對不是
Absolutely not.
真沒想到
I had no idea.
您想贏得勒芒賽
Now, you wanna win Le Mans.
如果您真的想贏得第一名
If you really wanna take first place,
肯·邁爾斯就是你的人選
Ken Miles is the man to do it.
來得真巧
Good timing.
他了解這車  因為是他幫我造的
Now, he knows this car because he helped me build it.
謝爾比  你知道我已經任命里奧·畢比
Shelby, you know I've already appointed Leo Beebe
-為賽車總監  -正因如此我才和您談
- director of racing. - Which is exactly why I'm talking to you.
您讓肯·邁爾斯在迪通拿耐力賽上場
Now, you let Ken Miles race Daytona.
如果他贏了
If he wins...
他就在勒芒賽上場
he gets to drive Le Mans.
如果他沒贏呢
And if he doesn't?
福特汽車公司獲得謝爾比美國公司的全部所有權
Ford Motor Company gets full ownership of Shelby American.
完全控制權  股份以及品牌
Lock, stock, and brand.
永遠
Forever.
迪通拿24小時耐力賽進行到第六個小時
We're in hour six at the Daytona 24,
福特車稱霸排行榜
and Fords are dominating the leaderboard.
謝爾比美國車隊的肯·邁爾斯稍微領先
Shelby American's Ken Miles holds a narrow lead
沃爾特·漢斯根駕駛的霍爾曼-穆迪車隊的福特
over the Holman-Moody Ford driven by Walt Hansgen.
我可不那么認為  沃爾特
I don't bloody think so, Walt.
這場比賽不只是對我們車輛的測驗
This race is not just a test of our cars,
也是對我們團隊的測驗
but also our teams.
你們也知道  我們今天有第二支團隊上場
As you know, we have a second team out there today.
-霍爾曼-穆迪車隊  -沒錯
- Holman-Moody. - That's right.
95號  漢斯根
Number 95, Hansgen,
飛馳過前部三角環道
blisters through the front tri-oval
逼近肯·邁爾斯
while closing in on Ken Miles.
沃爾特把車開得太快了
Walt's pushing her too fast.
他要開到七千轉
He's pushing 7,000 RPM.
把提示放慢的牌子放出去
Get the EZ sign out there.
快點  動起來  立刻去
Come on. Move. Do it now.
今天場上的每臺GT
Every one of these GTs out there today
都受我直接監管
is under my direct supervision.
當然還有亨利·福特二世
And of course the supervision of Henry Ford II.
車手  速度  策略
The drivers, the speed, the strategy...
甚至轉速都由我們決定
even the RPMs are determined by us.
肯·邁爾斯和漢斯根
Ken Miles is locked in a pitched battle
在經過大看臺時陷入酣戰
with Hansgen as they pass the grandstand.
漢斯根進入1號彎時逼近邁爾斯
Hansgen is taking a run at Miles entering turn one.
邁爾斯被擋死了
Miles is boxed in.
漢斯根成功超車并取得領先
Hansgen slips by and takes the lead
靠近內場連續彎
approaching the infield chicane.
天吶
Cor blimey!
你看到了嗎
Did you see that?
警告旗已出
The caution flag is out.
還在跑  我們的車還在跑
Still racing. We are still racing.
快  伙計們  上
Come on, guys, let's go!
行動  動起來
Let's go. Move it.
他要進站了
He's coming in.
快行動  伙計們  快
Let's go, let's go, guys. Come on.
快  把輪胎抬起來
Go, tires up.
就是這里  行動  動起來
Here, right here. Let's go. Let's go. Move it.
-油槍來了  -破除桿
- Fuel flying in. - Breaker bar!
-可以了  -檢查完畢
- We're good. - It all checked out.
-36  38  -快上
- 36. 38. - Go! Go!
漢斯根追得太緊了
Hansgen is right up our arse.
如果我能比他先開出維修站
If I can just get outta the pit ahead of him...
發動機溫度有點高  但我覺得可以撐下來
She's running hot, but I think she'll hold.
-燃油不足  -拿鏟子
- Fuel's low. - Bring up the scoop.
溫度有點高
She's hot.
你好  沃爾特  很高興見到你
Hey there, Walt. Good to see you.
等我開出這里  謝爾比
Yeah, after I get out of this pit, Shelby,
你就高興不起來了
it's the last time you will.
不用擔心
Don't worry.
我們有后視鏡
We got rearview mirrors.
被他逼出賽道的野馬怎么樣了
What happened to that Mustang he took out?
還不知道
Don't know yet.
我可以開到六千轉以上  謝爾
I can push her harder than six, Shel.
我能感覺到
I can feel it.
為什么這些人檢修加油比我們快這么多
How come these guys pit so much faster than we do?
因為他們有納斯卡車賽團隊
They got a goddamn NASCAR crew, that's why.
-不是吧  -是的
- No shit? - No shit.
快  快
Go! Go, come on.
可以了  可以了
We're clear, we're clear.
該死的納斯卡車賽團隊
Goddamn NASCAR crew.
出發  出發
Go, go, go!
伙計們  他們已經離開了
Guys, they've already left.
喂
Hello?
我的莫莉  你好
There's my Mollie. Hello.
你好  親愛的
Hiya, love.
-媽媽  媽媽  -你在做什么
- Mom? Mom? - What are you doing?
在喝茶
Just having a cuppa.
媽媽  問他剎車的情況
Mom, ask him about the brakes.
-去睡覺  已經凌晨一點了  -問他
- Go to bed. It's 1:00 a.M. - Ask him.
去睡覺  馬上
Go to bed. Now.
我猜他還沒睡
I take it he's not asleep.
他肯定偷偷拿了收音機
I'm sure he smuggled in a radio.
是啊
Yeah.
他讓我問  "剎車怎么樣了"
He said to ask, "How are the brakes?"
剎車  對  沒事
The brakes? Yes. No, no, no.
告訴他  剎車暫時還能用
Tell him they're working for now.
謝爾比一直表現得很奇怪
You know, Shelby's been acting very strange.
-福特已經去  -肯
- Ford have gone... - Ken.
組建了另一支隊伍
and put up another team.
-開一輛GT  -肯
- With a GT. - Ken.
某種愚蠢的狗屁公司測試之類的
Some sort of yampy, bloody corporate test or something.
我不知道  但是...
I don't know, but...
有機會的話就休息一會
Just take a rest whenever you get a chance.
抱歉  親愛的  你說什么
Sorry, my love, what were you saying?
你只有幾個小時了
You've only got a few hours.
我聽不太清楚
I can't hear you very well.
抱歉  我聽不清
I'm sorry. I can't hear you.
祝我好運吧
Wish me luck.
-祝你好運  -我愛你  親愛的
- Good luck. - I love you, darling.
迪通拿耐力賽已經進行了23小時
After 23 hours here at Daytona,
駕駛著綠白色福特的沃爾特·漢斯根
Walt Hansgen driving the green and white Ford
遙遙領先肯·邁爾斯和謝爾比美國車隊
has a commanding lead over Ken Miles and Shelby American
其他選手都已經落下一大截
as the rest of the field has fallen off the pace.
我們輸定了
We're locked out.
比賽到這階段邁爾斯也無能為力了
Ain't nothing Miles can do this late in the race.
發動機過熱  我們要把轉速壓在六千以下
Engine's hot. We gotta keep it under six thou.
上到七千轉
拼命沖刺
好啊
All right.
車可能會散架的
She could come apart.
不試試怎么知道
One way to find out.
我們不是讓他別超過六千轉嗎
I thought we were keeping him under 6,000?
閉嘴  唐
Shut up, Don.
迪通拿耐力賽僅剩下最后幾分鐘
With only minutes of racing left here at Daytona,
爭奪第一名的決戰突然打響
a pitched battle for the lead is being waged
福特98號在比賽的最后發起驚人的沖刺
as the number 98 Ford makes an incredible late surge.
-怎么了  -他在加速
- What's happening? - He's moving up.
進入了前部三角環道
...entering the front tri-oval,
肯·邁爾斯志在奪冠的最后一搏可能會...
Ken Miles' desperate bid for the win may prove to be...
加油
Come on now!
白旗  最后一圈
White flag! Last lap!
邁爾斯把他逼得很緊
Miles is pushing him. Hard.
就是這樣  寶貝
That's it, girl.
肯·邁爾斯緊跟沃爾特·漢斯根
Ken Miles drafts Walt Hansgen
進入了最后一個彎道
coming into the final turn.
快呀  快呀
Come on. Come on.
搞什么
What the hell?
加油
Come on.
好了
All right.
好好看著吧
Look at this now.
媽的
Damn it!
肯·邁爾斯奪得第一
Ken Miles takes the checkered flag,
為謝爾比美國車隊爭得榮耀
bringing glory to Shelby American.
怎么樣啊
How about that?
可靠性  強度...
Reliability, strength...
喂  里奧
Yes, Leo.
福特先生  我們贏了
Mr. Ford, sir, we won.
我們贏了  福特贏了迪通拿耐力賽
We won! Ford won Daytona.
太好了
Hot damn.
哪支隊贏了  里奧
And which team was it, Leo?
謝爾比美國車隊  車手是邁爾斯
Shelby American. Miles driving.
這混蛋
Son of a bitch.
好了
All right.
他到底去哪了
Where the hell is he?
等等  我看見他了  等下
Hang on, I see him. Hey, wait.
有人在沙灘上走失一條斗牛犬
Someone lost a bulldog on the beach.
別別  快來吧
No, no. Come on. Come on.
快來  來來來
Come on. Let's go. Let's go.
快把酒給他  把酒給他
Someone get this man a drink. Someone get him a drink.
快睡覺  你在做什么呢
In bed, you. What are you doing?
夜貓子
Dirty stop out.
我是在...
I was...
畫地圖  這樣就能知道你在勒芒的賽況
drawing a map, so I could follow you on Le Mans.
看看
Look at that.
畫得完全正確
That is spot on.
你真是高手  非常準確
You are a dab hand, very accurate.
跟我說說賽道吧
Tell me about the track.
不行  彼得
No, I can't, Petey.
求你了
Please.
從起點線出發
Well, you start at the start line.
對  但你其實是從這里出發的
Yeah, but you actually start here
因為在勒芒賽你得跑向你的車
because you have to run to your car at Le Mans.
沒錯
True enough.
一旦你老爸成功挪過去
So, once your old man manages to hobble over...
-把車開出來  -還沒撞到別的車
- and pull out... - And not hit anyone.
對  沒錯
Yes, right.
然后就要全力加速開往鄧洛普橋
Then you accelerate very hard up to Dunlop Bridge...
路向一邊傾斜
road banking away from ya
經過樹叢就到了埃索斯連續彎
and down through the trees to the Esses...
再加速進入特魯熱加速彎
and accelerate up to Tertre Rouge.
這是個關鍵的一檔彎
Critical first gear corner.
快速入彎
Fast entry.
保持高速出彎  進入...
Keep your speed up for your exit onto...
慕尚直道
Mulsanne.
這是一段很長的直路  被白楊簇擁著
Long straightaway, hemmed in by poplars.
掛最高檔  開到時速338公里
Top gear, 210 miles per hour.
然后退到三檔  提高轉速
And down to third, revs up.
轉速就是你的朋友
Revs are your friend.
最遠距離入彎  讓車空檔滑行
Get a maximum exit. Let the car run free.
經過坡頂
Over the brow...
然后...
then...
經過慕尚彎
Mulsanne Corner.
一路加速到雅致彎
Accelerate to Arnage
然后爬坡至白屋彎
and then over the rise to the White House.
過好這個彎...
You get that right and...
24小時比賽里的第一個三分半
your first three and a half minutes...
就過去了
of 24 hours.
但是  你沒法做到每圈都很完美
But... you can't make every lap perfect.
但我可以盡力
But I can try.
好了
All right.
快上床睡覺了
Off to bed, you.
我會先來叫醒你
I will... wake you...
然后再動身去法國
before I leave for France.
我保證
I promise.
好  晚安
Okay. Good night.
那個...
Where's, um...
圣皮埃爾大酒店怎么走
Where's that? The Hotel Saint Pierre?
哪里
Where?
明天還會再下雨的
It's gonna rain again tomorrow.
這里成天下雨
There's always rain here.
但開賽時沒有雨
Start'll be dry though,
所以等下雨了我們再幫你換輪胎
so we'll swap out your tires come rain.
好
Yeah.
你還是好好睡一覺比較好  斗牛犬
Might be smart to sleep, Bulldog.
你也一樣
Well, you, too.
又不是我開車
I'm not driving.
那還真是可惜了
That's a bloody shame, that.
我沒那技術
Oh, hell, I couldn't make this team.
我要走到第一個彎道
I'm gonna go walk the first corner.
我猜到了
I figured.
就靠這個了
Counting on it.
肯
Ken.
查茲
Chaz.
我們要改一下座椅的顏色
We'll change the color of the seats,
對吧  弗羅斯特
shall we, Frost?
如果這是選美大賽的話
Well, if this were a beauty pageant...
我們已經輸了
we just lost.
看起來跑得挺快  不是嗎
Looks fast, don't it?
外表可說明不了一切
Looks aren't everything.
法拉利是斯卡費奧提和班蒂尼開賽
Scarfiotti and Bandini start for Ferrari.
你能贏他
You can take him.
四分鐘  肯  還有四分鐘  伙計
Four minutes, Ken. Four minutes, buddy.
這里是來自法國勒芒的現場直播
Live from Le Mans, France.
媽  快來
Mom! Come on.
好了  來了
All right, coming.
勒芒24小時耐力賽
The 24 Hours of Le Mans.
賽車已經排成一列
And there are the cars lined up...
車手請就位
Drivers, please take your places.
-車手們就在那里  -他在那里
- And there they are... - There he is.
站成一排  蓄勢待發
lined up, ready to go.
法國勒芒衛星實況轉播
他們按照練習賽的用時排位
They're lined up as per their practice times.
更快的車排在我們左邊
Faster cars are up to our left.
你他媽在逗我吧
Oh, bloody joking!
比扎瑞尼十號幾乎失控
Number 10, a Bizzarrini, almost loses control.
沒事的
It's all right.
您剛剛看起來好極了  先生
You looked great out there, sir.
邁爾斯怎么了
What happened to Miles?
鄧洛普
天啊
Bloody hell.
不
No.
狗娘養的
Poxy bastard.
一圈過后
After one lap,
法拉利的班蒂尼占據首位
Bandini-Ferrari is in first place.
邁爾斯在哪
Where is Miles?
肯跑哪去了
Where the hell is Ken?
我不知道
I don't know.
他要進站了
He's coming in.
他要進站了  動起來
He's going in. Let's go.
弗羅斯特  快點  快動起來
Frosty, come on. Let's go. Move it.
我覺得是車門出了問題
I think it's his door.
福特車隊早早就出師不利
That's a rough start for the Ford team so early...
這該死的門關不上
The bloody door won't close!
沒事  沒事  我們會解決的
All right. All right. We'll take care of it.
快點  伙計們
Come on, guys.
這破車門
Damn door!
-試試  -這樣應該就行了
- Try that. - This'll do it.
謝爾比  出什么問題了
Shelby, what the hell is wrong?
有東西卡著門框
Something's hitting the frame.
你在逗我吧
Oh, you're joking, aren't ya?
所有人讓開
Guys, get outta the way.
都讓開  扶好了
Just get outta the way. Hold it.
走  快走
Go! Go, go, go!
他重新上道了
He's back out.
上吧
Go.
肯·邁爾斯駕駛著謝爾比美國車隊的
Ken Miles, in Shelby American's
福特1號  目前排名第十
Ford number 1, in tenth place.
駕駛福特1號的肯·邁爾斯行駛里程劇增
Tremendous gains for Ken Miles in Ford number 1.
-加油  爸爸  -超過了保時捷43號
- Come on, Dad. Come on. - Passing Porsche 43.
迅速擠入前二十  他在不斷超車...
Moving quickly into the top 20. He's passing them...
肯·邁爾斯  刷新了最快圈速
Ken Miles, Ford, has set a new lap record.
3分34秒
Three minutes and 34 seconds.
-太好了  -肯·邁爾斯用3分34秒3跑完一圈
- Yeah! - Ken Miles passed it with a time of 3:34.3.
謝爾比
Shelby.
他開得太猛了  計劃不是這樣的
He's pushing the car too hard. That's not the plan.
計劃是會變的
Plans change.
上圈3分34秒  賽道13.5公里
Last 3.34. Track is 8.36.
來個人告訴我他的時速
Someone tell me the miles per hour!
3分31秒9
Three minutes, 31.9.
法國勒芒衛星實況轉播
-又刷新了最快圈速  -他的平均速度為
- Another lap record! - That's an average speed
229公里每小時
of 142.01 miles per hour.
快上  動起來  小伙子們
Let's go. Let's go, boys.
茶泡好了  肯
Tea's ready, Ken.
謝了  查茲
Oh, thank you, Chaz.
-生日快樂  老伙計  -謝謝  老兄  開得太棒了
- Happy birthday, old chap! - Cheers, mate. Great run.
快上  小伙子們  動作快點
Go, boys. Move, move, move.
需要快速檢查車身
Need a quick body check!
你比格尼快三秒
You're three seconds faster than Gurney.
要是一開始沒出問題  你現在就領先了
If you hadn't blown the start, you'd be in the lead.
你能保持這個速度嗎
Can you keep this up?
車行我就行
Can the car?
六號彎發生事故
There has been an incident on turn six.
18號車與26號車相撞
Number 18 and number 26 have collided.
看起來法拉利20號
It appears Ferrari number 20,
盧多維科·斯卡費奧蒂  也退出了賽道
Ludovico Scarfiotti, has also left the track.
法拉利20號
-好了  小心碰頭  -上去吧
- All right, watch your head. - Here you go.
謝謝
Thank you.
祝您用餐愉快  先生
Have a good dinner, sir.
邁凱倫進站了
Oi, McLaren's pitting.
福特先生可能要去個高級的地方用晚餐了
Mr. Ford's probably going somewhere nice for dinner.
這不是明擺著嗎
What do you mean "Probably"?
快下雨了
Rain's coming.
知道了
All right.
進站了
Coming in.
把輪胎抬起來
Go, tires up!
快檢查一下
Get 'em checked out.
發動機溫度有點高  老爹
Engine's running hot, Pops.
-了解  -溫度有點高了  老兄  繼續開吧
- All right. - She's hot, mate. Crack on.
-快  -好樣的  丹尼
- Go. - Well done, Denny.
輪胎接好
Tire.
儀表盤沒問題
Dash clear.
換下來
Swap.
發動機溫度104度  還可以
We're at 220. We're okay.
知道了
All right.
油槍來了
Fuel flying in.
后輪放在墻邊
Rear tires coming up the wall!
把油加進去  快點
Get the fuel in there. Come on. Let's go.
換下來
Swap that out.
前胎換好了
Front set.
好了
We're good.
-跑起來  -快  快
- Get it moving! - Go! Go!
快走
Go, go!
好樣的  伙計們  好樣的
Good job, guys. Good job.
配合不錯  伙計們
It was a good change, fellas.
給我拿一只秒表
Hey, I need a stopwatch.
24小時的賽程已過八小時  法拉利車隊包攬前二
看到了嗎  那位美國汽車工業巨頭坐直升機走了  真是高級
法拉利車隊的洛倫佐·班迪尼
Lorenzo Bandini remains
仍然占據第一
in first place for Ferrari.
悠著點  丹  你被擋死了
Easy, Dan. You're getting boxed in.
他可不是傻子
He's not batting on a full wicket, that one.
慢慢來  丹
Easy, Dan.
該死
Oh, bloody hell!
你這個混蛋
You arsehole.
滾開
Oh, piss off!
你這個混蛋
You wanker!
這下被撞得稀巴爛了吧
A face like a smacked arse, now, don't ya?
保時捷58號和一輛身份不明的福特
Porsche number 58 with an unidentified Ford
在雅致彎沖出賽道
are run off the track at Arnage.
快點  肯  加油
Go, Ken. Come on, Ken.
秒表不錯
Nice stopwatch.
你想來一個嗎  意大利貨
You want one? They're Italian.
駕駛福特1號的肯·邁爾斯
Ken Miles in Ford number 1
和駕駛法拉利21號的班迪尼
and Bandini in Ferrari 21
在這樣惡劣的天氣條件下互不相讓
are locked in a battle against the elements
他們以極限速度
as they push their cars to the limit
通過白屋彎
past the White House corner.
現在由于下雨
And now with all that rain,
賽道變得又濕又滑
the track conditions are wet and slippery
預計高速圈會受到影響
so expect these very fast laps to suffer.
有什么指示  先生
Yes, sir?
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
明白  先生
是  先生  我馬上去
Okay, sir. Right away, sir.
肯·邁爾斯  注意減速
你干什么呢  把牌子給我
What the hell are you doing? Give me that.
白癡
Dumbass.
謝爾比先生
Mr. Shelby...
就是現在
Here we go.
快呀  寶貝
Come on, girl.
加把勁
Come on.
堅持住
Hold it together now.
天吶
God!
媽的  快呀
Bugger! Come on.
現在領先的是洛倫佐·班迪尼駕駛的
The leader at this moment is Ferrari number 21
法拉利21號
being driven by Lorenzo Bandini.
他的剎車失靈了  準備起來
His brakes are shot. All right, here we go.
肯·邁爾斯非常緩慢地把福特1號
It looks like Ken Miles is bringing the number 1 Ford
開進了維修站  可能是出了什么...
into the pits very slowly. He could have a...
馬上進站  大家注意了
Coming in. Watch yourself, guys.
-剎車  沒反應  一點都沒有  -知道了
- Brakes. Nothing. Gone. - Yeah.
動作快點  快點  快點
All right. Let's go, let's go, let's go.
我就要超過他了  差一點就超過他了
I had him. I almost had him.
他現在領先我們一圈了
Well, he's putting another lap on us now.
好了  裝上  先裝前輪
All right. Fit it in. Do the upper arm first.
快點  速度快點  再快點
Come on, let's go. Come in now, now. Faster.
趕緊的
Let's go.
先裝前輪
Upper arm first.
小心制動管路  輕點拽
Watch the brake line pulling it out.
他們在換剎車
They're doing it. The brakes.
這會花費...
Now, that's gonna take...
我說了  小心制動管路
I said watch the brake line.
快點  再快點
Faster! Faster! Faster!
過來了  當心身后
Coming in. Watch your back!
杰夫  動作再快點
Jeff, you've gotta be faster!
法拉利車隊
給剎車放氣  杰夫
Bleed the brakes, Jeff.
不行不行
No, no, no.
這是違規行為  你不能想怎么改就怎么改
It's against the rules. You cannot just change things.
不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
告訴我你的手冊上哪里寫了
You show me where it says in your book
我們不能更換剎車系統
that we cannot swap out the system,
只要你能找到  隨便你取消我們的資格
and then you can disqualify us.
斗牛犬  退后
Bulldog, back off.
冷靜點  冷靜
Calm down. Calm down.
這是不合法的
This is not legal.
你告訴我規則手冊里哪一條規定了
You show me where it says in that little rule book
我不能換掉豎式總成
where I can't swap out my upright assembly.
零件就是零件
A part is a part.
不管是剎車鉗  剎車盤還是豎式總成
Be it a brake caliper, a rotor, or an upright assembly,
我想換什么就換什么
and I can swap out any damn thing I want to.
別以為我們沒讀過規則手冊
We read your damn rule book.
班迪尼進站了  他進站了
Bandini's pitting. He's pitting.
真是可惜
Oh, what a shame.
可能是壞了一條管路
I think he blew a line.
因為他剛剛想跟上你的速度
Well, he was trying to keep up with you.
雖然我不懂意大利語  但是看得出來他不高興
I don't speak Italian, but he ain't happy.
我得趕緊出發了  老爹
Get me out of here, Pops.
-快點  -知道了
- Come on! - All right.
快點
Come on!
馬上就好  肯  馬上就好
Almost there, Ken. Almost there.
怎么樣了  兄弟
How's it looking, buddy?
再充點氣  就可以了
One pump, and we're good.
可以出發了  肯
Car's yours, Ken.
聽好了  你還有贏他的機會
All right, listen, you can still take him,
但是你得超過他兩次
but you gotta pass him twice.
知道了  超過他兩次
I get it. Pass him twice.
肯·邁爾斯駕駛的福特1號重回賽道
Ford number 1 driven by Ken Miles is back out,
緊緊咬著班迪尼的法拉利21號
hot on the heels of Bandini in Ferrari 21.
還不夠好  邁爾斯  再加把勁
Not bloody good enough, Miles! Come on!
他慢下來了
He's off his pace.
他現在對車還是沒有信心
He doesn't trust the car yet.
加油  肯  剎車我都給你換好了
Come on, Ken. I gave you new brakes, buddy.
好好想想
All right.
你來這里是為了什么
What did you come here for?
放手一搏吧
Let's do it.
成了  加油
That's it! Come on!
他還沒做到
He ain't done it yet.
他還需要再追一圈
He needs to take another lap on him.
福特1號  肯·邁爾斯
他需要盡快進站
He needs to pit soon.
先追上班迪尼再說
He needs to catch Bandini first.
來吧  你這個混蛋
All right, you bastard.
我們再來一次
Let's do this again.
快呀
Come on, now.
好樣的  好樣的
That's my girl! That's my girl!
我的天吶  我的天吶
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
媽的
Bloody hell!
他做到了  我們領先了
He did it. We're in the lead.
我們領先了嗎
Are we in the lead?
班迪尼呢
What about Bandini?
班迪尼在哪
Where's Bandini?
他們完了  結束了
They're done. Finished.
法拉利完了
Ferrari's over.
邁凱輪的GT落后他四分鐘
McLaren's four minutes behind him in a GT.
現在肯排第一
So we're lying Ken first,
第二和第三  也都是福特
and two and three. All Fords.
法拉利21號
Ferrari number 21
和車手班迪尼已經離開賽道
and driver Bandini have left the track.
大魔王來了
The Deuce is coming.
肯半小時后就要上了  要我叫醒他嗎
Ken's up in a half an hour. Want me to wake him?
不  讓他睡吧
Nah, let him sleep.
-非常感謝  -不可思議
- Thank you very much. - Unbelievable.
您好  福特先生
Hello. Mr. Ford.
比賽還沒有結束  不過
We're not quite there yet, but...
你錯過了一頓美餐
You missed a good meal.
他來了  他來了
There he is. There he is.
現在進展如何  里奧
Brief me, Leo.
前三名都是我們的車  福特先生
We're running one, two, three, Mr. Ford.
領頭的是誰
Who's in the lead?
赫爾姆和邁爾斯
Hulme, Miles.
我有一個想法  福特先生
You know, I was thinking, Mr. Ford...
要是我們的三臺車可以排成一排
wouldn't it be great if all three Fords lined up
同時沖過終點  那該多壯觀
and crossed the finish line at the exact same time?
他們排成一排  一起回家
They all lined up and came home together.
三臺福特  并駕齊驅
Ford. Ford. Ford.
我覺得不太可能做到  先生
I don't think we can actually do that, sir, but...
為什么不能
Why not?
邁爾斯現在領先不止一圈  里奧
Miles is laps ahead, Leo.
你想讓他怎么做  減速嗎
What would you have him do, slow down?
是啊
Yeah.
福特先生想讓邁爾斯減減
Mr. Ford wants Miles to slow down.
他希望三輛車可以同時沖過終點
He wants all three cars to cross at the exact same time.
他認為對福特來說  這將會是歷史性的一刻
He thinks it'll be a historic moment for Ford.
拍出來的照片一定賞心悅目
It'll make a great photograph.
謝爾比  邁爾斯現在要發揮團隊精神
Shelby, Miles needs to be a team player here,
你也一樣
and so do you.
你來告訴他  還是我來說
You gonna tell him, or you need me to?
離我的車手遠一點  走開
Don't go near my driver. Go on.
這是福特先生的要求
This is what Mr. Ford wants.
給我走開
Go on now.
-他希望看到你們的忠誠  -走開
- He expects loyalty. - Go on.
行動起來  小伙子們  動作快點
Guys, let's go. Come on. All right, look lively, boys.
快點  弗羅斯特
Let's go. Frosty.
來了
Yeah, coming.
快點
Let's go. Come on.
畢比要干什么
What's Beebe want?
看來是很過分的要求
It's off the scale, innit?
他們想讓你減速
They want you to slow down.
你再說一遍
Run that by me again.
他們想讓你減速
They want you to slow down.
肯  你讓他們的車相形見絀了
You're outshining their car, Ken.
你領先了邁凱倫四分鐘
You're four minutes up on McLaren.
大魔王希望福特的三輛車
The Deuce wants the three Fords
分別以第一  第二  第三名一起沖過終點線
to cross the finish line one, two, three, all together.
他們要求你有些團隊精神
They're asking that you be a team player...
幫助他們拍下那樣一張照片
and make that photograph happen for 'em.
就為了拍張照片  他們真行啊
That photograph. That's good.
真會想
That is good.
肯  即便你和他們并列奪冠
Ken, even if you tie for first...
你仍然是史上第一個在同一年內奪下
you'd still be the first man ever to win...
賽百靈  迪通拿  和勒芒三項賽事冠軍的人
Sebring, Daytona, and Le Mans in the same year.
你將成為三冠王
You'd have the triple crown.
聽著  我沒有...
Look, I ain't get...
我從第一天開始
I haven't been able to get you
就無法讓你服從命令
to follow an order since day one.
無論你想怎么做我都可以接受
Whatever you wanna do is fine with me.
我做主嗎
My choice?
你做主
Your choice.
發動機已經快到極限了
The engine's running at boiling.
剎車也快不行了
The brakes are shot.
安排好了嗎
How was that?
都搞定了
Taken care of.
車準備好了  肯
The car's yours, Ken.
肯  車為你準備好了
Ken, the car's yours.
肯
Ken!
可以出發了  肯
Car's yours, Ken.
所有車手都在追趕福特車隊
It's the Fords that are the cars to beat,
此刻他們的三輛車包攬了前三名
claiming the top three positions...
他到底在做什么
What the hell is he doing?
肯·邁爾斯駕駛著福特1號位居第一
led by Ken Miles in Ford number 1...
不許接
Don't answer that.
離電話遠點
Get away from it.
駕駛著福特1號的肯·邁爾斯
Ken Miles in Ford number 1 is demonstrating
此刻正以他超凡的車技
why he's one of the top drivers here at Le Mans
展示著為何他是勒芒賽上最出色的車手之一
with an outstanding display of skill.
觀眾們請瞧好福特1號
Keep an eye on Ford number 1.
他要破他自己的紀錄了
He's gonna break his own record.
別說話
Shut up.
等等
Wait for it.
再等等
就現在
Now.
邁爾斯  邁爾斯  邁爾斯
Miles. Miles. Miles.
很漂亮
Bellissimo.
3分30秒6  他又刷新紀錄了
3.30.6. That's another record.
肯·邁爾斯時再次刷新了最快圈速
Another lap record falls to Ken Miles...
這是完美的一圈
It's a perfect lap.
打破了他自己的紀錄
...breaking his own record
以此為謝爾比美國車隊
and virtually guaranteeing first place for Shelby American
以及他們出色的GT40確保了冠軍
and their exciting GT40.
駕駛著謝爾比美國車隊福特1號的肯·邁爾斯
Ken Miles in Shelby America's Ford number 1
剛剛打破了他自己創下的圈速紀錄
just beat his own lap record.
3分30秒6
Three minutes and 30.6 seconds...
讓他進站
Bring him in.
馬上讓他進站  他已經失控了
Right now! He's outta control.
在他毀了那輛車  使我們無法完成比賽之前
Now, you bring him in before he wrecks that car
讓他進站
and we don't finish.
讓他進站  謝爾比
Bring him in, Shelby,
否則我讓SCCA和FIA把你的車隊禁了
or I will get you banned from the SCCA and the FIA.
SCCA  美國賽車俱樂部
FIA  國際汽車聯盟
現在開車的人是肯·邁爾斯  里奧
Ken Miles is behind the wheel, Leo.
如何完成比賽由他決定
That's his car to the finish.
? 快快樂樂 ?
♪ H-a-p-p-y ♪
? 我快快樂樂 ?
♪ I'm h-a-p-p-y ♪
? 我確定一定以及肯定自己很快樂 ?
♪ I know I am, I'm sure I am ♪
快呀  伙計們  怎么還沒追上來
Come on, lads, where are ya?
-這真是難得一見的賽況  -他在做什么
- That is quite a sight to see. - What's he doing?
媽媽  他為什么在減速
Mum, why is he slowing down?
第二名和第三名的福特賽車緊隨其后
...the second and third place Fords to close ranks.
三輛福特將會同時沖過終點
The three Fords are going to cross the line together.
肯·邁爾斯減速了  等他的隊友追上
Ken Miles slowed down. He waited for them.
-現在三輛福特并排前行  -爸爸  不要
- Here are the Fords lined up in a row... - Dad. No.
-沒事的  -爸爸
- It's all right .- Dad.
-沒事的  -一  二  三
- It's all right. - One, two, three.
他帶領著他們
Look, he's bringing them in.
由肯·邁爾斯引領...
Led by Ken Miles...
他帶領他們一起沖過終點
He's bringing them all in together.
他毫無疑問是此隊的引領者...
...certainly the leader of this group
-他剛剛創下勒芒賽...  -干得好
- and owner of the Le Mans lap record... - Good for you.
-最快圈速紀錄  -肯  干得好
- ...set just moments ago. - Good for you, Ken.
太好了  太好了
Yeah! Yeah!
瞧瞧這場面
Look at that.
-干得漂亮  里奧  -你也是  唐
- Well done, Leo. - You too, Don.
請稍等
Please stand by.
最終賽果正在審核
Final results are under review.
和我解釋一下為什么他最先沖過終點
...is explain to me how he's finished first
卻不是第一名
and he's not won the race?
因為邁凱倫的起點更靠后
Because McLaren started from further,
所以他更...  他贏了
so he came in... he won.
結果不是并列第一
Look, it's not a tie.
不是并列  因為邁凱倫
No, because McLaren...
因為邁凱倫的起點更靠后
Because McLaren started further back,
他說他的行駛里程更多一些
he's saying he's traveled that little bit further,
所以他贏了  而不是肯
so he's won and not Ken.
行駛里程更多  他贏了
It's a longer distance. He won.
這太扯了  胡扯
That is bullshit. That's bullshit.
謝爾  等等
Shel! Hold on!
并列第一呢
Where's the tie?
你他媽不是說并列第一嗎
Where's the goddamn tie?
-什么  -你這個王八蛋
- What? - You son of a bitch!
-謝爾比  -你早知道會這樣
- Shelby! - You knew!
不  我并不知道
No, I didn't know!
-夠了  夠了  -放開我
- That's enough! Enough! - Get off me!
布魯斯
Bruce.
賽得漂亮  兄弟  祝賀
Nice race, mate. Congrats.
謝爾
Shel!
他們搶了你冠軍  肯
They robbed you, Ken.
以下是對賽果的澄清
Here is the clarification.
雖然三名車手同時沖過終點線
Though the drivers finished the race in a heat,
但因為邁凱倫的起點更靠后
McLaren has been ruled the winner
他被裁定為冠軍
as he started from farther back.
都是些胡扯的技術細節
Some bullshit technicality.
最終結果  由邁凱倫和阿蒙駕駛的
Final results. Ford number 2,
福特2號  贏得了比賽的冠軍
driven by McLaren and Amon, is the winner.
由邁爾斯和赫爾姆駕駛的福特1號
Ford number 1, driven by Miles and Hulme,
獲得了亞軍
second place.
季軍是由巴克奴和哈切森
In third place, Bucknum and Hutcherson
駕駛的福特5號
in Ford number 5.
我根本不該和你說
I never should've asked you.
都是為了賣車  對吧
Selling cars, huh?
他們就是干這個的
That's what they do.
你許諾過讓我駕駛
Well, you promised me the drive.
沒許諾過奪冠
Not the win.
你開得太棒了
It was a hell of a drive.
是我們的車很棒
She's a hell of a machine.
它確實很快
She's fast.
還能更快
Could be faster.
7L發動機確實性能絕佳
The 7 liter's sweet...
不過
but...
我們仍然需要輕一些的底盤
we still need a lighter chassis.
我在考慮使用復合鋁材
I was thinking bonded aluminium.
我們要從頭開始打造  但如果能成
It's a ground-up rebuild, but if it works...
可以減輕幾百斤車重
we can lose a couple hundred pounds.
那我們還在這浪費什么時間
Well, what the hell are we doing here?
讓我回去洗個澡  喝杯茶
Let me take a shower, get a cup of tea...
再來點火腿奶酪夾面包什么的
ham and cheese cob or something.
我們明年再來贏這些王八蛋
We're gonna get the bastards next year.
油缸里還剩一點汽油
Got a bit of fuel left in the tank.
你覺得那些蜂窩板結構的底盤怎么樣
What do you think of those honeycomb panels?
是你想要的嗎
What you were looking for?
還不知道
Don't know yet.
這車看起來相當棒
She looks pretty good.
在七千轉時  有一個臨界點
There's a point, at 7,000 RPM...
一切都變得虛無
where everything fades.
車失去了重量
The machine becomes weightless.
直接消失了
Just disappears.
爽
Yeah!
只留下一具軀殼
And all that's left is a body...
在時空中穿梭
moving through space and time.
七千轉
7,000 RPM.
就是那個臨界點
That's where you meet it.
你能感覺到它的來臨
You feel it coming.
它悄悄地逼近你  來到你的耳邊
It creeps up on you, close in your ear.
向你提出一個問題
Asks you a question.
一個終極的問題
The only question that matters.
把貨車開過來
Get the van!
"你究竟是誰"
"Who are you?"
感覺如何
What do you think?
太棒了  感覺好極了
It's fantastic. Feels really good.
駕駛感流暢
Nice and smooth.
變速箱沒有振動  感覺馬力強勁
No vibration in the box. Feels really strong.
你才開了不到一小時
You drove it for less than an hour.
你能感覺出來個屁
You can't tell shit after an hour.
每輛車七千塊整  總共就是一萬四
Go for seven even, that'd be 14 all in.
謝爾
Shel.
賽道之星
謝爾  那個家伙  就是那個戴帽子的
Shel, that guy, you know the one in the hat,
他已經決定下單兩輛眼鏡蛇427
he's ready to close on those two 427s.
他和他太太一人一輛  全額運費
His and hers. Full freight.
他們是從加爾溫斯頓飛過來的
They, flew in from Galveston.
我需要你出來個一兩分鐘
I need you to come outside for maybe a minute.
做什么
And do what?
做卡羅爾·謝爾比
Be Carroll Shelby.
給他們講個故事  說點吉祥話
Tell them a story, spin a few magic words.
"吉祥話"是什么意思
What does that mean? "Magic words"?
我的意思是
It means...
出來跟他們打個招呼
come outside and say hello
讓他們這個錢花得心里舒服
and make them feel good about their purchase.
他們買的是車
They're getting the damn cars.
他們花了錢  車就歸他們了  菲爾
That's what they get for their money, Phil.
要買就買  不買拉倒
Now, either they want 'em or they don't.
-我難道是個戲子嗎  -不是
- Am I some kind of a lounge act? - No.
我難道是個搞推銷的嗎
Am I here to talk people into things?
已經過去六個月了  謝爾
It's been six months, Shel.
六個月了
Six months.
有時候他們不會活著下車
Sometimes they don't get out of the car.
彼得
Peter!
彼得  來把垃圾搬出去
Peter, come and take the garbage out.
謝爾比先生
Mr. Shelby.
你好  彼得
Hello, Pete.
我記得那把扳手
I remember that wrench.
我爸爸拿它扔了你
My dad threw it at you.
是的
I believe he did.
為什么
Why?
好像因為我對他說了些什么
I think I probably said something to him.
罵了他幾句
Called him a few names.
沒錯
That's right.
你要找我媽媽嗎
Do you wanna speak to my mum?
我是想找她
Well, I did.
我想來打個招呼  看她過得好不好  還有...
I came to say hello, check in on her and...
然后我想到  有時候
Then I started thinking that sometimes...
言語...
words...
根本沒有任何用處
just... ar-are not useful.
工具是有用的  因為你能用它們造東西
Tools are useful 'cause you can make stuff with 'em
也能用它們修東西
and you can fix stuff with 'em.
給你
Here.
謝謝
Thanks.
你爸爸是...
Your daddy was...
他是你的朋友
He was your friend.
是的  他是我的朋友
Yes, he was.
沒錯  小伙子
Yes, sir.
他覺得你是個特別棒的孩子
And he thought you was just finer than frog fur.
彼得
Peter!
我得去幫媽媽干活了
I think I've gotta go help my mum.
那你還磨蹭什么呢  快去吧
What are you doing here then? Go on.
再見
Bye.
肯·邁爾斯深受全世界賽車迷的尊敬
入選賽車名人堂
卡羅爾·謝爾比成為了歷史上
最成功和最有名的賽車設計者之一
由謝爾比和邁爾斯研制的福特GT40
贏得了1966  1967  1968及1969年的勒芒耐力賽
是迄今為止唯一贏得過
勒芒24小時耐力賽的美國產賽車